<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Peilong Li</title>
    <link>https://Peilong.github.io/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://Peilong.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Peilong Li</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2019 Peilong Li</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://Peilong.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Peilong Li</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Overview</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs121/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs121/overview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-coverage&#34;&gt;Course Coverage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fundamental concepts of computer organization, machine-level representation of data, algorithmic development and structured programming are presented with an emphasis on the syntactic and execution characteristics of the Java programming language, including data types; arithmetic operators and assignment; input/output, selection and iteration constructs; procedural abstraction; arrays; object-oriented programming and class design; and library usage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;student-learning-outcomes&#34;&gt;Student Learning Outcomes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of the course, students will be able to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apply knowledge of computing and mathematics, including common data structures and basic algorithms, to solve problems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design, implement, and evaluate a computer-based system, process, component or program to meet desired needs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Describe fundamental principles of the cycle of designing, implementing, compiling, and testing code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn to adhere to standards of style and documentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop an understanding of data types and basic operations in an object-oriented programming language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give examples of contributions of mathematics and computer science to the modern world&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use inductive or deductive reasoning to formulate solutions to problems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Model real-world phenomena mathematically and computationally&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manipulate strings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use basic I/O constructs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apply Boolean algebra and selection statements to problem solving&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apply loop statements to problem solving&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apply static methods to improve code design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apply arrays to store aggregate data for problem solving&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use procedural and object-oriented programming paradigms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Overview</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs222/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs222/overview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-coverage&#34;&gt;Course Coverage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This course covers advanced programming and machine representation of data and data structures, including dynamic structures and files. Topics include C language syntax, memory allocation, run-time data organization, function linkage and parameter passing, and the relationship between high-level and machine languages. C is the primary language of instruction with Java being a comparative language. Linux operating system and command line skills will be introduced throughout the course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;student-learning-outcomes&#34;&gt;Student Learning Outcomes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of the course, students will be able to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apply knowledge of computing and mathematics appropriate to the discipline, including common data structures and basic algorithms, to solve problems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analyze a problem and identify and define the computing requirements appropriate to its solution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design, implement, and evaluate a computer-based system, process, component or program, including operating systems, to meet desired needs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Function effectively on teams and use software engineering principles to accomplish a common goal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understand fundamentals of procedural programming with applications in electrical and computer engineering and embedded systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understand hardware and software elements of data communications and computer networking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compare and contrast the features of the Java and C programming languages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manage memory allocation explicitly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perform low-level file access in programs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Overview</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs400/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs400/overview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-coverage&#34;&gt;Course Coverage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This course is a directed project or study requiring faculty acceptance of a proposal with a final report and defense of work. It is intended as a capstone course for Computer Science and Information Systems majors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;student-learning-outcomes&#34;&gt;Student Learning Outcomes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of the course, students will be able to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apply knowledge of computing and mathematics appropriate to the discipline, including common data structures and basic algorithms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analyze a problem and identify and define the computing requirements appropriate to its solution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design, implement, and evaluate a computer-based system, process, component or program, including operating systems and database systems, to meet desired needs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Communicate effectively with a broad range of audiences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Engage in continuing professional development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Overview</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs495/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs495/overview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-coverage&#34;&gt;Course Coverage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This course is a directed project or study requiring faculty acceptance of a proposal with a final report and defense of work. It is intended as an advanced research course for Computer Science majors and a prerequisite for Honors in the Discipline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;student-learning-outcomes&#34;&gt;Student Learning Outcomes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of the course, students will be able to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apply knowledge of computing and mathematics appropriate to the discipline, including common data structures and basic algorithms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analyze a problem and identify and define the computing requirements appropriate to its solution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design, implement, and evaluate a computer-based system, process, component or program, including operating systems and database systems, to meet desired needs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Communicate effectively with a broad range of audiences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Engage in continuing professional development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Overview</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/ds200/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/ds200/overview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-coverage&#34;&gt;Course Coverage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project-based hands-on course introduces students to data science in general. Data science is an interdisciplinary field that applies computer science and statistics to extract useful knowledge from data collected in an almost unlimited range of other disciplines, including business, biology, physics, medicine, meteorology, and many others. In this course, students will apply the popular Python data science toolset to implement analytical models with k-nearest neighbors, regression, decision trees, and clustering, etc., and infer knowledge from real-world data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;student-learning-outcomes&#34;&gt;Student Learning Outcomes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Introduction) Understand the background and rationale behind this new data science discipline.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Hacking) Proficiently use the Python data science toolset including Jupyter notebook, NumPy, Pandas, Scikit-learn etc., in the lab assignments and projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Visualization) Use data visualization python packages Matplotlib and Seaborn to present analytical results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Statistics) Reinforce the understanding of statistics and its application in the scope of data science.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Analytics) Apply data analytical models including regression, clustering and decision trees to solve data science problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Overview</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/ds300/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/ds300/overview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-coverage&#34;&gt;Course Coverage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project-based hands-on course covers various data processing techniques in the data mining pipeline such as 1) data extraction from large data warehouses, 2) data preprocessing to obtain data features, 3) data modeling and data training, and 4) knowledge generation. A number of well-defined data mining tasks such as classification, prediction, association, clustering, dimensionality reduction and deep learning are thoroughly discussed. Design and implementation issues for the aforementioned tasks are also addressed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;student-learning-outcomes&#34;&gt;Student Learning Outcomes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of the course, the successful students will be able to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Scope) Understand the background and application scope of data mining.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Data) Extract raw data from SQL databases using data science toolkit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Hacking) Proficiently use the Python data science toolset including Jupyter notebook, NumPy, Pandas, Scikit-learn, Seaborn and Tensorflow etc. to address data mining tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Modeling) Apply data analytical models including regression, clustering and neural network to solve data science problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Knowledge) Obtain knowledge from the data with the various models.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Overview</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/ds420/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/ds420/overview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-coverage&#34;&gt;Course Coverage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This course covers techniques needed to collect, store, analyze, and visualize big data, particularly for applications in machine learning at scale. The MapReduce paradigm will be taught using the popular Hadoop framework. Both batch and real-time analysis of massive quantities of data will be applied to machine learning problems such as clustering, regression, and classification. Although the relational database model will be discussed, NoSQL models will have primary focus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;student-learning-outcomes&#34;&gt;Student Learning Outcomes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of the course, the successful students will be able to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Hadoop Ecosystem) Design distributed systems that manage &amp;ldquo;big data&amp;rdquo; using Hadoop and related technologies in the Hadoop Ecosystem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Scalability) Use HDFS and MapReduce for storing and analyzing data at scale.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Programmability) Use Pig and Spark to create scripts to process data on a Hadoop cluster in more complex and programmable ways.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Databases) Analyze relational data using Hive and MySQL, and analyze non-relational data using HBase and MongoDB. Learn to choose an appropriate data storage technology for your application&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Machine Learning) Deploy machine learning models at scale to process distributed big data using Spark MLlib.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Management) Understand how Hadoop clusters are managed by Big Data Framework Managers like YARN, Mesos, Zookeeper and Oozie, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Real-time Analysis) Publish data to computing clusters using Kafka and Flume. Consume streaming data using Spark Streaming and Storm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Overview</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/ds495/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/ds495/overview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-coverage&#34;&gt;Course Coverage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This course is a directed project or study requiring faculty acceptance of a proposal with a final report and defense of work. It is intended as an advanced research course for Data Science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under the supervision of a faculty mentor, students use their knowledge of data science to complete a high level project contributing to research in an academic area or to solve a problem for a local business. Projects will involve data collection, data cleaning, data analysis, and reporting results both orally and in writing to a domain expert or business leader. All problems are unstructured with no predetermined solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;student-learning-outcomes&#34;&gt;Student Learning Outcomes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of the course, students will be able to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apply knowledge of data science appropriate to the discipline, including advanced skills like big data parallel processing and neural networks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analyze a problem and identify and define the data analytical requirements and procedure appropriate to its solution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design and implement a computer-based system, process, component or program, to address an open data problem (including open data competitions hosted on Kaggle)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Communicate effectively with a broad range of audiences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Engage in continuing professional development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Policy Statements</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs121/policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs121/policy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-schedule&#34;&gt;Course Schedule&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most up-to-date course schedule will be posted on course website schedule page: &lt;a href=&#34;https://peilong.github.io/courses/cs121/schedule/&#34;&gt;https://peilong.github.io/courses/cs121/schedule/&lt;/a&gt;. Students are responsible for checking the schedule regularly. Schedule page will include: 1) teaching topics for each meeting; 2) reading assignments for each week and 3) special notes on specific days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-announcements--discussion&#34;&gt;Course Announcements &amp;amp; Discussion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All course announcements will be sent to your Etown email accounts via Canvas Announcements. You are responsible for signing up for this service and checking your emails regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every student should have received my invitation to join our team &amp;ldquo;CS121 Computer Science I FA20&amp;rdquo; on Microsoft Teams. Discussions are encouraged to be posted on the &amp;ldquo;QA&amp;rdquo; channel of the team. Private instant messages can be sent directly to your recipient, e.g. the instructor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Missing my email to join Teams? Click this &lt;a href=&#34;https://teams.microsoft.com/l/team/19%3a7bc4be22948c423eb2a0ac0662b19cd9%40thread.tacv2/conversations?groupId=d034bbc2-ce2b-4aeb-9e5a-65a604fa1dab&amp;amp;tenantId=1d884f12-a0d7-42f0-8b15-3a91c853bcb5&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt; again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;attendance-policies&#34;&gt;Attendance Policies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attendance is expected of every student at every lecture. Students are responsible for all content covered in class as well as assigned book chapters. Due to their nature, pop quizzes cannot be made up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except in the case of documented emergencies, neither exams nor in-class labs can be made up afterwards.  For excused absences, students must arrange to take the exam or do the lab before the normally scheduled time.  Arrangements must be made with the instructor at least two weeks prior to the scheduled time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students are expected to maintain an attitude of respect at all times toward their colleagues, the equipment, and the instructor. Students are expected to refrain from using the computers for non-course related purposes during class time and will be penalized 1% of the final grade for each occurrence. Cell phones and similar devices should be turned off before entering the classroom. Students who use offensive language, misuse computing facilities, or are otherwise disruptive of the classroom will be asked to leave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;statement-on-school-closure&#34;&gt;Statement on School Closure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the event that classes do not meet because Elizabethtown College is closed or delayed due to inclement weather or some other emergency, the slides that would have been covered during the missed classes will posted through Piazza group.  Students are expected to do the assigned reading, review the slides, and e-mail the instructor with any questions.  There will also be an opportunity to ask questions about the material when classes resume.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a scheduled exam or lab is missed, it will normally be made up on the day that classes resume.  If the College is closed on a day when a project is due, the project due date will also normally be extended until the day when classes resume.  If circumstances render either of these makeup policies unreasonable, the instructor will send an e-mail explaining an alternative makeup opportunity to each student’s Elizabethtown e-mail account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;statement-on-plagiarism&#34;&gt;Statement on Plagiarism&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please refer to the Student Handbook for the college’s policy.  All projects and assignments must be completed by students individually, without assistance from anyone other than the instructor.  Students can discuss the course material with each other at a conceptual level, but each student must do his or her own work.  For projects, exams, and all other activities in the course, students are expected to act according to the official policy on academic dishonesty and the highest standards of personal integrity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first infraction of academic honesty in this course will carry a penalty of a 0 for the project, lab, or exam in question and a reduction of a full letter grade in the final grade.  If a second infraction occurs, the students involved will fail the course, and the instructor will seek the maximum penalty possible under the college’s regulations, up to and including expulsion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;statement-on-disability&#34;&gt;Statement on Disability&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Full statement can be found at &lt;a href=&#34;https://elizabethtown-my.sharepoint.com/:w:/g/personal/ouimetc_etown_edu/EfZ-QooKt_VPjgwsWJz230wB3Rb6CIHsPvE0xuqWCpr-UA?e=4%3acZzjpW&amp;amp;at=9&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;. Elizabethtown College welcomes otherwise qualified students with disabilities to participate in all of its courses, programs, services, and activities. If you have a documented disability and would like to request accommodations in order to access course material, activities, or requirements, please contact the Director of Disability Services, Lynne Davies, by phone (361-1227) or e-mail &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:daviesl@etown.edu&#34;&gt;daviesl@etown.edu&lt;/a&gt;. If your documentation meets the college’s documentation guidelines, you will be given a letter from Disability Services for each of your professors.  Students experiencing certain documented temporary conditions, such as post-concussive symptoms, may also qualify for temporary academic accommodations and adjustments. As early as possible in the semester, set up an appointment to meet with the instructor to discuss the academic adjustments specified in your accommodations letter as they pertain to my class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;covid-related-expectations&#34;&gt;COVID-related Expectations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All students are expected to adhere to the established community expectations around safety, including: daily digital health reporting, physical distancing, proper wearing of facial coverings within buildings and classrooms and when within six feet of individuals outdoors, frequent handwashing, and participation in cleaning and sanitizing protocols as requested. You will be turned away from class if you do not have a face covering. Students diagnosed with a health condition that precludes mask wearing can contact Lynne Davies in Disability Services (&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:daviesl@etown.edu&#34;&gt;daviesl@etown.edu&lt;/a&gt;) to request remote learning as a reasonable accommodation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are exhibiting any symptoms of COVID or fail to pass the daily health screen, do not come to class.
Failure to adhere to the established community expectations around safety will result in notification of Campus Security and application of the student conduct process for failure to comply, endangering the well-being of others, and/or disorderly conduct. The student code of conduct applies also to participation in all virtual activities, including Zoom sessions and discussion boards&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;statement-on-religious-observances&#34;&gt;Statement on Religious Observances&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The College is eager to facilitate individual religious beliefs and practices whenever possible while retaining course student learning outcomes. It is your responsibility to meet with the class instructor in advance to request arrangements related to your religious observances that may conflict with this class, and to make appropriate plans to make up any missed work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Policy Statements</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs222/policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs222/policy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-announcements--discussion&#34;&gt;Course Announcements &amp;amp; Discussion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All course announcements will be posted via the Canvas Announcements page – you are responsible for checking the email updates (or app notifications) from Canvas regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discussions can be made via the Canvas Discussion page – you should never post complete programs to Discussion page (only general questions are permitted).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Need to DM (direct message) me? Join my Discord Q&amp;amp;A server: &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/32KEYEn&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;attendance-policies&#34;&gt;Attendance Policies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attendance is expected of every student at every lecture.  Students are responsible for all content covered in class as well as assigned book chapters.  Students should come to class with their text books, having read the material to be covered that day.  Students who have not prepared for class may be asked to leave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except in the case of documented emergencies, neither exams nor in-class labs can be made up afterwards.  For excused absences, students must arrange to take the exam or do the lab before the normally scheduled time.  Arrangements must be made with the instructor at least two weeks prior to the scheduled time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students are expected to maintain an attitude of respect at all times toward their colleagues, the equipment, and the instructor.  Students are expected to refrain from using the computers for non-course related purposes during class time and will be penalized 1% of the final grade for each occurrence.  Cell phones and similar devices should be turned off before entering the classroom.  Students who use offensive language, misuse computing facilities, or are otherwise disruptive of the classroom will be asked to leave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;statement-on-school-closure&#34;&gt;Statement on School Closure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the event that classes do not meet because Elizabethtown College is closed or delayed due to inclement weather or some other emergency, the slides that would have been covered during the missed classes will posted through Piazza group.  Students are expected to do the assigned reading, review the slides, and e-mail the instructor with any questions.  There will also be an opportunity to ask questions about the material when classes resume.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a scheduled exam or lab is missed, it will normally be made up on the day that classes resume.  If the College is closed on a day when a project is due, the project due date will also normally be extended until the day when classes resume.  If circumstances render either of these makeup policies unreasonable, the instructor will send an e-mail explaining an alternative makeup opportunity to each student’s Elizabethtown e-mail account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;statement-on-plagiarism&#34;&gt;Statement on Plagiarism&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please refer to the Student Handbook for the college’s policy.  All projects and assignments must be completed by students individually, without assistance from anyone other than the instructor.  Students can discuss the course material with each other at a conceptual level, but each student must do his or her own work.  For projects, exams, and all other activities in the course, students are expected to act according to the official policy on academic dishonesty and the highest standards of personal integrity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first infraction of academic honesty in this course will carry a penalty of a 0 for the project, lab, or exam in question and a reduction of a full letter grade in the final grade.  If a second infraction occurs, the students involved will fail the course, and the instructor will seek the maximum penalty possible under the college’s regulations, up to and including expulsion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;statement-on-disability&#34;&gt;Statement on Disability&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elizabethtown College welcomes otherwise qualified students with disabilities to participate in all of its courses, programs, services, and activities. If you have a documented disability and would like to request accommodations in order to access course material, activities, or requirements, please contact the Director of Disability Services, Lynne Davies, by phone (361-1227) or e-mail &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:daviesl@etown.edu&#34;&gt;daviesl@etown.edu&lt;/a&gt;. If your documentation meets the college’s documentation guidelines, you will be given a letter from Disability Services for each of your professors.  Students experiencing certain documented temporary conditions, such as post-concussive symptoms, may also qualify for temporary academic accommodations and adjustments. As early as possible in the semester, set up an appointment to meet with the instructor to discuss the academic adjustments specified in your accommodations letter as they pertain to my class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;statement-on-religious-observances&#34;&gt;Statement on Religious Observances&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The College is eager to facilitate individual religious beliefs and practices whenever possible while retaining course student learning outcomes. It is your responsibility to meet with the class instructor in advance to request arrangements related to your religious observances that may conflict with this class, and to make appropriate plans to make up any missed work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Policy Statements</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs400/policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs400/policy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-announcements--discussion&#34;&gt;Course Announcements &amp;amp; Discussion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All course announcements will be posted via the Canvas Announcements page – you are responsible for checking the email updates (or app notifications) from Canvas regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discussions can be made via the Canvas Discussion page – you should never post complete programs to Discussion page (only general questions are permitted).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Need to DM (direct message) me? Join my Discord Q&amp;amp;A server: &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/32KEYEn&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;attendance-policies&#34;&gt;Attendance Policies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attendance is expected of every student at every meeting. Students should come to meetings prepared to explain their progress and discuss appropriate technical issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;statement-on-school-closure&#34;&gt;Statement on School Closure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the event that classes do not meet because Elizabethtown College is closed or delayed due to inclement weather or some other emergency, the slides that would have been covered during the missed classes will posted through Piazza group.  Students are expected to do the assigned reading, review the slides, and e-mail the instructor with any questions.  There will also be an opportunity to ask questions about the material when classes resume.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a scheduled exam or lab is missed, it will normally be made up on the day that classes resume.  If the College is closed on a day when a project is due, the project due date will also normally be extended until the day when classes resume.  If circumstances render either of these makeup policies unreasonable, the instructor will send an e-mail explaining an alternative makeup opportunity to each student’s Elizabethtown e-mail account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;statement-on-plagiarism&#34;&gt;Statement on Plagiarism&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please refer to the Student Handbook for the college’s policy.  All projects and assignments must be completed by students individually, without assistance from anyone other than the instructor.  Students can discuss the course material with each other at a conceptual level, but each student must do his or her own work.  For projects, exams, and all other activities in the course, students are expected to act according to the official policy on academic dishonesty and the highest standards of personal integrity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first infraction of academic honesty in this course will carry a penalty of a 0 for the project, lab, or exam in question and a reduction of a full letter grade in the final grade.  If a second infraction occurs, the students involved will fail the course, and the instructor will seek the maximum penalty possible under the college’s regulations, up to and including expulsion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;statement-on-disability&#34;&gt;Statement on Disability&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elizabethtown College welcomes otherwise qualified students with disabilities to participate in all of its courses, programs, services, and activities. If you have a documented disability and would like to request accommodations in order to access course material, activities, or requirements, please contact the Director of Disability Services, Lynne Davies, by phone (361-1227) or e-mail &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:daviesl@etown.edu&#34;&gt;daviesl@etown.edu&lt;/a&gt;. If your documentation meets the college’s documentation guidelines, you will be given a letter from Disability Services for each of your professors.  Students experiencing certain documented temporary conditions, such as post-concussive symptoms, may also qualify for temporary academic accommodations and adjustments. As early as possible in the semester, set up an appointment to meet with the instructor to discuss the academic adjustments specified in your accommodations letter as they pertain to my class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;statement-on-religious-observances&#34;&gt;Statement on Religious Observances&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The College is eager to facilitate individual religious beliefs and practices whenever possible while retaining course student learning outcomes. It is your responsibility to meet with the class instructor in advance to request arrangements related to your religious observances that may conflict with this class, and to make appropriate plans to make up any missed work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Policy Statements</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs495/policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs495/policy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-announcements--discussion&#34;&gt;Course Announcements &amp;amp; Discussion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All course announcements will be posted via the Canvas Announcements page – you are responsible for checking the email updates (or app notifications) from Canvas regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discussions can be made via the Canvas Discussion page – you should never post complete programs to Discussion page (only general questions are permitted).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Need to DM (direct message) me? Join my Discord Q&amp;amp;A server: &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/32KEYEn&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;attendance-policies&#34;&gt;Attendance Policies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attendance is expected of every student at every meeting. Students should come to meetings prepared to explain their progress and discuss appropriate technical issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;statement-on-school-closure&#34;&gt;Statement on School Closure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the event that classes do not meet because Elizabethtown College is closed or delayed due to inclement weather or some other emergency, the slides that would have been covered during the missed classes will posted through Piazza group.  Students are expected to do the assigned reading, review the slides, and e-mail the instructor with any questions.  There will also be an opportunity to ask questions about the material when classes resume.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a scheduled exam or lab is missed, it will normally be made up on the day that classes resume.  If the College is closed on a day when a project is due, the project due date will also normally be extended until the day when classes resume.  If circumstances render either of these makeup policies unreasonable, the instructor will send an e-mail explaining an alternative makeup opportunity to each student’s Elizabethtown e-mail account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;statement-on-plagiarism&#34;&gt;Statement on Plagiarism&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please refer to the Student Handbook for the college’s policy.  All projects and assignments must be completed by students individually, without assistance from anyone other than the instructor.  Students can discuss the course material with each other at a conceptual level, but each student must do his or her own work.  For projects, exams, and all other activities in the course, students are expected to act according to the official policy on academic dishonesty and the highest standards of personal integrity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first infraction of academic honesty in this course will carry a penalty of a 0 for the project, lab, or exam in question and a reduction of a full letter grade in the final grade.  If a second infraction occurs, the students involved will fail the course, and the instructor will seek the maximum penalty possible under the college’s regulations, up to and including expulsion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;statement-on-disability&#34;&gt;Statement on Disability&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Full statement can be found at &lt;a href=&#34;https://elizabethtown-my.sharepoint.com/:w:/g/personal/ouimetc_etown_edu/EfZ-QooKt_VPjgwsWJz230wB3Rb6CIHsPvE0xuqWCpr-UA?e=4%3acZzjpW&amp;amp;at=9&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;. Elizabethtown College welcomes otherwise qualified students with disabilities to participate in all of its courses, programs, services, and activities. If you have a documented disability and would like to request accommodations in order to access course material, activities, or requirements, please contact the Director of Disability Services, Lynne Davies, by phone (361-1227) or e-mail &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:daviesl@etown.edu&#34;&gt;daviesl@etown.edu&lt;/a&gt;. If your documentation meets the college’s documentation guidelines, you will be given a letter from Disability Services for each of your professors.  Students experiencing certain documented temporary conditions, such as post-concussive symptoms, may also qualify for temporary academic accommodations and adjustments. As early as possible in the semester, set up an appointment to meet with the instructor to discuss the academic adjustments specified in your accommodations letter as they pertain to my class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;covid-related-expectations&#34;&gt;COVID-related Expectations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All students are expected to adhere to the established community expectations around safety, including: daily digital health reporting, physical distancing, proper wearing of facial coverings within buildings and classrooms and when within six feet of individuals outdoors, frequent handwashing, and participation in cleaning and sanitizing protocols as requested. You will be turned away from class if you do not have a face covering. Students diagnosed with a health condition that precludes mask wearing can contact Lynne Davies in Disability Services (&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:daviesl@etown.edu&#34;&gt;daviesl@etown.edu&lt;/a&gt;) to request remote learning as a reasonable accommodation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are exhibiting any symptoms of COVID or fail to pass the daily health screen, do not come to class.
Failure to adhere to the established community expectations around safety will result in notification of Campus Security and application of the student conduct process for failure to comply, endangering the well-being of others, and/or disorderly conduct. The student code of conduct applies also to participation in all virtual activities, including Zoom sessions and discussion boards&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;statement-on-religious-observances&#34;&gt;Statement on Religious Observances&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The College is eager to facilitate individual religious beliefs and practices whenever possible while retaining course student learning outcomes. It is your responsibility to meet with the class instructor in advance to request arrangements related to your religious observances that may conflict with this class, and to make appropriate plans to make up any missed work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Policy Statements</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/ds200/policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/ds200/policy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-announcements--discussion&#34;&gt;Course Announcements &amp;amp; Discussion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All course announcements will be posted via the Canvas Announcements page – you are responsible for checking the email updates (or app notifications) from Canvas regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discussions can be made via the Canvas Discussion page – you should never post complete programs to Discussion page (only general questions are permitted).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Need to DM (direct message) me? Join my Discord Q&amp;amp;A server: &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/32KEYEn&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;attendance-policies&#34;&gt;Attendance Policies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attendance is expected of every student at every lecture.  Students are responsible for all content covered in class as well as assigned book chapters.  Students should come to class with their text books, having read the material to be covered that day.  Students who have not prepared for class may be asked to leave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except in the case of documented emergencies, neither exams nor in-class labs can be made up afterwards.  For excused absences, students must arrange to take the exam or do the lab before the normally scheduled time.  Arrangements must be made with the instructor at least two weeks prior to the scheduled time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students are expected to maintain an attitude of respect at all times toward their colleagues, the equipment, and the instructor.  Students are expected to refrain from using the computers for non-course related purposes during class time and will be penalized 1% of the final grade for each occurrence.  Cell phones and similar devices should be turned off before entering the classroom.  Students who use offensive language, misuse computing facilities, or are otherwise disruptive of the classroom will be asked to leave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;statement-on-school-closure&#34;&gt;Statement on School Closure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the event that classes do not meet because Elizabethtown College is closed or delayed due to inclement weather or some other emergency, the slides that would have been covered during the missed classes will posted through Piazza group.  Students are expected to do the assigned reading, review the slides, and e-mail the instructor with any questions.  There will also be an opportunity to ask questions about the material when classes resume.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a scheduled exam or lab is missed, it will normally be made up on the day that classes resume.  If the College is closed on a day when a project is due, the project due date will also normally be extended until the day when classes resume.  If circumstances render either of these makeup policies unreasonable, the instructor will send an e-mail explaining an alternative makeup opportunity to each student’s Elizabethtown e-mail account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;statement-on-plagiarism&#34;&gt;Statement on Plagiarism&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please refer to the Student Handbook for the college’s policy.  All projects and assignments must be completed by students individually, without assistance from anyone other than the instructor.  Students can discuss the course material with each other at a conceptual level, but each student must do his or her own work.  For projects, exams, and all other activities in the course, students are expected to act according to the official policy on academic dishonesty and the highest standards of personal integrity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first infraction of academic honesty in this course will carry a penalty of a 0 for the project, lab, or exam in question and a reduction of a full letter grade in the final grade.  If a second infraction occurs, the students involved will fail the course, and the instructor will seek the maximum penalty possible under the college’s regulations, up to and including expulsion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;statement-on-disability&#34;&gt;Statement on Disability&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elizabethtown College welcomes otherwise qualified students with disabilities to participate in all of its courses, programs, services, and activities. If you have a documented disability and would like to request accommodations in order to access course material, activities, or requirements, please contact the Director of Disability Services, Lynne Davies, by phone (361-1227) or e-mail &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:daviesl@etown.edu&#34;&gt;daviesl@etown.edu&lt;/a&gt;. If your documentation meets the college’s documentation guidelines, you will be given a letter from Disability Services for each of your professors.  Students experiencing certain documented temporary conditions, such as post-concussive symptoms, may also qualify for temporary academic accommodations and adjustments. As early as possible in the semester, set up an appointment to meet with the instructor to discuss the academic adjustments specified in your accommodations letter as they pertain to my class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;statement-on-religious-observances&#34;&gt;Statement on Religious Observances&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The College is eager to facilitate individual religious beliefs and practices whenever possible while retaining course student learning outcomes. It is your responsibility to meet with the class instructor in advance to request arrangements related to your religious observances that may conflict with this class, and to make appropriate plans to make up any missed work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Policy Statements</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/ds300/policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/ds300/policy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-schedule&#34;&gt;Course Schedule&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most up-to-date course schedule will be posted on course website schedule page: &lt;a href=&#34;https://peilong.github.io/courses/ds300/schedule/&#34;&gt;https://peilong.github.io/courses/ds300/schedule/&lt;/a&gt;. Students are responsible for checking the schedule regularly. Schedule page will include: 1) teaching topics for each meeting; 2) reading assignments for each week and 3) special notes on specific days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-announcements--discussion&#34;&gt;Course Announcements &amp;amp; Discussion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All course announcements will be sent to your Etown email accounts via Canvas Announcements. You are responsible for signing up for this service and checking your emails regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every student should have received my invitation to join our team &amp;ldquo;DS300 Data Mining FA20&amp;rdquo; on Microsoft Teams. Discussions are encouraged to be posted on the &amp;ldquo;QA&amp;rdquo; channel of the team. Private instant messages can be sent directly to your recipient, e.g. the instructor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Missing my email to join Teams? Click this &lt;a href=&#34;https://teams.microsoft.com/l/team/19%3aa8cdd959c2e249a989d401e20fc95524%40thread.tacv2/conversations?groupId=81ffa3c7-aa45-454a-b495-7f43c78e5024&amp;amp;tenantId=1d884f12-a0d7-42f0-8b15-3a91c853bcb5&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt; again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;attendance-policies&#34;&gt;Attendance Policies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attendance is expected of every student at every lecture. Students are responsible for all content covered in class as well as assigned book chapters. Due to their nature, pop quizzes cannot be made up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except in the case of documented emergencies, neither exams nor in-class labs can be made up afterwards.  For excused absences, students must arrange to take the exam or do the lab before the normally scheduled time.  Arrangements must be made with the instructor at least two weeks prior to the scheduled time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students are expected to maintain an attitude of respect at all times toward their colleagues, the equipment, and the instructor. Students are expected to refrain from using the computers for non-course related purposes during class time and will be penalized 1% of the final grade for each occurrence. Cell phones and similar devices should be turned off before entering the classroom. Students who use offensive language, misuse computing facilities, or are otherwise disruptive of the classroom will be asked to leave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;statement-on-school-closure&#34;&gt;Statement on School Closure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the event that classes do not meet because Elizabethtown College is closed or delayed due to inclement weather or some other emergency, the slides that would have been covered during the missed classes will posted through Piazza group.  Students are expected to do the assigned reading, review the slides, and e-mail the instructor with any questions.  There will also be an opportunity to ask questions about the material when classes resume.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a scheduled exam or lab is missed, it will normally be made up on the day that classes resume.  If the College is closed on a day when a project is due, the project due date will also normally be extended until the day when classes resume.  If circumstances render either of these makeup policies unreasonable, the instructor will send an e-mail explaining an alternative makeup opportunity to each student’s Elizabethtown e-mail account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;statement-on-plagiarism&#34;&gt;Statement on Plagiarism&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please refer to the Student Handbook for the college’s policy.  All projects and assignments must be completed by students individually, without assistance from anyone other than the instructor.  Students can discuss the course material with each other at a conceptual level, but each student must do his or her own work.  For projects, exams, and all other activities in the course, students are expected to act according to the official policy on academic dishonesty and the highest standards of personal integrity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first infraction of academic honesty in this course will carry a penalty of a 0 for the project, lab, or exam in question and a reduction of a full letter grade in the final grade.  If a second infraction occurs, the students involved will fail the course, and the instructor will seek the maximum penalty possible under the college’s regulations, up to and including expulsion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;statement-on-disability&#34;&gt;Statement on Disability&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Full statement can be found at &lt;a href=&#34;https://elizabethtown-my.sharepoint.com/:w:/g/personal/ouimetc_etown_edu/EfZ-QooKt_VPjgwsWJz230wB3Rb6CIHsPvE0xuqWCpr-UA?e=4%3acZzjpW&amp;amp;at=9&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;. Elizabethtown College welcomes otherwise qualified students with disabilities to participate in all of its courses, programs, services, and activities. If you have a documented disability and would like to request accommodations in order to access course material, activities, or requirements, please contact the Director of Disability Services, Lynne Davies, by phone (361-1227) or e-mail &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:daviesl@etown.edu&#34;&gt;daviesl@etown.edu&lt;/a&gt;. If your documentation meets the college’s documentation guidelines, you will be given a letter from Disability Services for each of your professors.  Students experiencing certain documented temporary conditions, such as post-concussive symptoms, may also qualify for temporary academic accommodations and adjustments. As early as possible in the semester, set up an appointment to meet with the instructor to discuss the academic adjustments specified in your accommodations letter as they pertain to my class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;covid-related-expectations&#34;&gt;COVID-related Expectations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All students are expected to adhere to the established community expectations around safety, including: daily digital health reporting, physical distancing, proper wearing of facial coverings within buildings and classrooms and when within six feet of individuals outdoors, frequent handwashing, and participation in cleaning and sanitizing protocols as requested. You will be turned away from class if you do not have a face covering. Students diagnosed with a health condition that precludes mask wearing can contact Lynne Davies in Disability Services (&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:daviesl@etown.edu&#34;&gt;daviesl@etown.edu&lt;/a&gt;) to request remote learning as a reasonable accommodation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are exhibiting any symptoms of COVID or fail to pass the daily health screen, do not come to class.
Failure to adhere to the established community expectations around safety will result in notification of Campus Security and application of the student conduct process for failure to comply, endangering the well-being of others, and/or disorderly conduct. The student code of conduct applies also to participation in all virtual activities, including Zoom sessions and discussion boards&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;statement-on-religious-observances&#34;&gt;Statement on Religious Observances&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The College is eager to facilitate individual religious beliefs and practices whenever possible while retaining course student learning outcomes. It is your responsibility to meet with the class instructor in advance to request arrangements related to your religious observances that may conflict with this class, and to make appropriate plans to make up any missed work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Policy Statements</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/ds420/policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/ds420/policy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-schedule&#34;&gt;Course Schedule&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most up-to-date course schedule will be posted on course website schedule page: &lt;a href=&#34;https://peilong.github.io/courses/ds420/schedule/&#34;&gt;https://peilong.github.io/courses/ds420/schedule/&lt;/a&gt;. Students are responsible for checking the schedule regularly. Schedule page will include: 1) teaching topics for each meeting; 2) reading assignments for each week and 3) special notes on specific days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-announcements--discussion&#34;&gt;Course Announcements &amp;amp; Discussion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All course announcements will be sent to your Etown email accounts via Canvas Announcements. You are responsible for signing up for this service and checking your emails regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every student should have received my invitation to join our team &amp;ldquo;DS420 Big Data FA20&amp;rdquo; on Microsoft Teams. Discussions are encouraged to be posted on the &amp;ldquo;QA&amp;rdquo; channel of the team. Private instant messages can be sent directly to your recipient, e.g. the instructor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Missing my email to join Teams? Click this &lt;a href=&#34;https://teams.microsoft.com/l/team/19%3a1f4763190259407691bb1a2c67ccefbc%40thread.tacv2/conversations?groupId=c6d7c74e-4549-43dc-b47e-10836ce4d728&amp;amp;tenantId=1d884f12-a0d7-42f0-8b15-3a91c853bcb5&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt; again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;attendance-policies&#34;&gt;Attendance Policies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attendance is expected of every student at every lecture. Students are responsible for all content covered in class as well as assigned book chapters. Due to their nature, pop quizzes cannot be made up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except in the case of documented emergencies, neither exams nor in-class labs can be made up afterwards.  For excused absences, students must arrange to take the exam or do the lab before the normally scheduled time.  Arrangements must be made with the instructor at least two weeks prior to the scheduled time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students are expected to maintain an attitude of respect at all times toward their colleagues, the equipment, and the instructor. Students are expected to refrain from using the computers for non-course related purposes during class time and will be penalized 1% of the final grade for each occurrence. Cell phones and similar devices should be turned off before entering the classroom. Students who use offensive language, misuse computing facilities, or are otherwise disruptive of the classroom will be asked to leave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;statement-on-school-closure&#34;&gt;Statement on School Closure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the event that classes do not meet because Elizabethtown College is closed or delayed due to inclement weather or some other emergency, the slides that would have been covered during the missed classes will posted through Piazza group.  Students are expected to do the assigned reading, review the slides, and e-mail the instructor with any questions.  There will also be an opportunity to ask questions about the material when classes resume.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a scheduled exam or lab is missed, it will normally be made up on the day that classes resume.  If the College is closed on a day when a project is due, the project due date will also normally be extended until the day when classes resume.  If circumstances render either of these makeup policies unreasonable, the instructor will send an e-mail explaining an alternative makeup opportunity to each student’s Elizabethtown e-mail account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;statement-on-plagiarism&#34;&gt;Statement on Plagiarism&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please refer to the Student Handbook for the college’s policy.  All projects and assignments must be completed by students individually, without assistance from anyone other than the instructor.  Students can discuss the course material with each other at a conceptual level, but each student must do his or her own work.  For projects, exams, and all other activities in the course, students are expected to act according to the official policy on academic dishonesty and the highest standards of personal integrity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first infraction of academic honesty in this course will carry a penalty of a 0 for the project, lab, or exam in question and a reduction of a full letter grade in the final grade.  If a second infraction occurs, the students involved will fail the course, and the instructor will seek the maximum penalty possible under the college’s regulations, up to and including expulsion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;statement-on-disability&#34;&gt;Statement on Disability&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Full statement can be found at &lt;a href=&#34;https://elizabethtown-my.sharepoint.com/:w:/g/personal/ouimetc_etown_edu/EfZ-QooKt_VPjgwsWJz230wB3Rb6CIHsPvE0xuqWCpr-UA?e=4%3acZzjpW&amp;amp;at=9&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;. Elizabethtown College welcomes otherwise qualified students with disabilities to participate in all of its courses, programs, services, and activities. If you have a documented disability and would like to request accommodations in order to access course material, activities, or requirements, please contact the Director of Disability Services, Lynne Davies, by phone (361-1227) or e-mail &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:daviesl@etown.edu&#34;&gt;daviesl@etown.edu&lt;/a&gt;. If your documentation meets the college’s documentation guidelines, you will be given a letter from Disability Services for each of your professors.  Students experiencing certain documented temporary conditions, such as post-concussive symptoms, may also qualify for temporary academic accommodations and adjustments. As early as possible in the semester, set up an appointment to meet with the instructor to discuss the academic adjustments specified in your accommodations letter as they pertain to my class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;covid-related-expectations&#34;&gt;COVID-related Expectations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All students are expected to adhere to the established community expectations around safety, including: daily digital health reporting, physical distancing, proper wearing of facial coverings within buildings and classrooms and when within six feet of individuals outdoors, frequent handwashing, and participation in cleaning and sanitizing protocols as requested. You will be turned away from class if you do not have a face covering. Students diagnosed with a health condition that precludes mask wearing can contact Lynne Davies in Disability Services (&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:daviesl@etown.edu&#34;&gt;daviesl@etown.edu&lt;/a&gt;) to request remote learning as a reasonable accommodation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are exhibiting any symptoms of COVID or fail to pass the daily health screen, do not come to class.
Failure to adhere to the established community expectations around safety will result in notification of Campus Security and application of the student conduct process for failure to comply, endangering the well-being of others, and/or disorderly conduct. The student code of conduct applies also to participation in all virtual activities, including Zoom sessions and discussion boards&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;statement-on-religious-observances&#34;&gt;Statement on Religious Observances&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The College is eager to facilitate individual religious beliefs and practices whenever possible while retaining course student learning outcomes. It is your responsibility to meet with the class instructor in advance to request arrangements related to your religious observances that may conflict with this class, and to make appropriate plans to make up any missed work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Policy Statements</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/ds495/policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/ds495/policy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-announcements--discussion&#34;&gt;Course Announcements &amp;amp; Discussion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All course announcements will be posted via the Canvas Announcements page – you are responsible for checking the email updates (or app notifications) from Canvas regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discussions can be made via the Canvas Discussion page – you should never post complete programs to Discussion page (only general questions are permitted).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Need to DM (direct message) me? Join my Discord Q&amp;amp;A server: &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/32KEYEn&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;attendance-policies&#34;&gt;Attendance Policies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attendance is expected of every student at every meeting. Students should come to meetings prepared to explain their progress and discuss appropriate technical issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;statement-on-school-closure&#34;&gt;Statement on School Closure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the event that classes do not meet because Elizabethtown College is closed or delayed due to inclement weather or some other emergency, the slides that would have been covered during the missed classes will posted through Piazza group.  Students are expected to do the assigned reading, review the slides, and e-mail the instructor with any questions.  There will also be an opportunity to ask questions about the material when classes resume.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a scheduled exam or lab is missed, it will normally be made up on the day that classes resume.  If the College is closed on a day when a project is due, the project due date will also normally be extended until the day when classes resume.  If circumstances render either of these makeup policies unreasonable, the instructor will send an e-mail explaining an alternative makeup opportunity to each student’s Elizabethtown e-mail account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;statement-on-plagiarism&#34;&gt;Statement on Plagiarism&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please refer to the Student Handbook for the college’s policy.  All projects and assignments must be completed by students individually, without assistance from anyone other than the instructor.  Students can discuss the course material with each other at a conceptual level, but each student must do his or her own work.  For projects, exams, and all other activities in the course, students are expected to act according to the official policy on academic dishonesty and the highest standards of personal integrity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first infraction of academic honesty in this course will carry a penalty of a 0 for the project, lab, or exam in question and a reduction of a full letter grade in the final grade.  If a second infraction occurs, the students involved will fail the course, and the instructor will seek the maximum penalty possible under the college’s regulations, up to and including expulsion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;statement-on-disability&#34;&gt;Statement on Disability&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Full statement can be found at &lt;a href=&#34;https://elizabethtown-my.sharepoint.com/:w:/g/personal/ouimetc_etown_edu/EfZ-QooKt_VPjgwsWJz230wB3Rb6CIHsPvE0xuqWCpr-UA?e=4%3acZzjpW&amp;amp;at=9&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;. Elizabethtown College welcomes otherwise qualified students with disabilities to participate in all of its courses, programs, services, and activities. If you have a documented disability and would like to request accommodations in order to access course material, activities, or requirements, please contact the Director of Disability Services, Lynne Davies, by phone (361-1227) or e-mail &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:daviesl@etown.edu&#34;&gt;daviesl@etown.edu&lt;/a&gt;. If your documentation meets the college’s documentation guidelines, you will be given a letter from Disability Services for each of your professors.  Students experiencing certain documented temporary conditions, such as post-concussive symptoms, may also qualify for temporary academic accommodations and adjustments. As early as possible in the semester, set up an appointment to meet with the instructor to discuss the academic adjustments specified in your accommodations letter as they pertain to my class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;covid-related-expectations&#34;&gt;COVID-related Expectations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All students are expected to adhere to the established community expectations around safety, including: daily digital health reporting, physical distancing, proper wearing of facial coverings within buildings and classrooms and when within six feet of individuals outdoors, frequent handwashing, and participation in cleaning and sanitizing protocols as requested. You will be turned away from class if you do not have a face covering. Students diagnosed with a health condition that precludes mask wearing can contact Lynne Davies in Disability Services (&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:daviesl@etown.edu&#34;&gt;daviesl@etown.edu&lt;/a&gt;) to request remote learning as a reasonable accommodation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are exhibiting any symptoms of COVID or fail to pass the daily health screen, do not come to class.
Failure to adhere to the established community expectations around safety will result in notification of Campus Security and application of the student conduct process for failure to comply, endangering the well-being of others, and/or disorderly conduct. The student code of conduct applies also to participation in all virtual activities, including Zoom sessions and discussion boards&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;statement-on-religious-observances&#34;&gt;Statement on Religious Observances&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The College is eager to facilitate individual religious beliefs and practices whenever possible while retaining course student learning outcomes. It is your responsibility to meet with the class instructor in advance to request arrangements related to your religious observances that may conflict with this class, and to make appropriate plans to make up any missed work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grading Policies</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs121/grading/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs121/grading/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;grading-weights&#34;&gt;Grading Weights&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final grade for this course depends upon the grades and scores earned on course components weighted as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12%&lt;/strong&gt;: 3 equally weighted projects - 4% for each.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20%&lt;/strong&gt;: 10 equally weighted in-class labs – 2% for each lab.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20%&lt;/strong&gt;: 2 equally weighted lab tests - 10% for each test.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20%&lt;/strong&gt;: 2 midterm exams - 10% for each exam.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6%&lt;/strong&gt;: Pop quizzes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2%&lt;/strong&gt;: Persistence. Attendance and in-class question answering.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20%&lt;/strong&gt;: Final exam.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grades will be computed by rounding numerical percentages to the nearest integer and applying the following table:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Letter&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Range&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Letter&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Range&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Letter&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Range&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;93-100&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;80-82&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;67-69&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;90-92&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;77-79&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;63-66&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;87-89&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;73-76&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;60-62&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;83-86&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;70-72&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0-59&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-Grades&#34;&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;projects&#34;&gt;Projects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All projects are team projects in this course. For each project, all students must form teams of two (or three in the case of an odd number of students). Students are permitted to select their own teams; however, no two students may partner up for more than one project. In other words, each team will be different for each project. Students should select their teams by using the Groups tab under People, on the Canvas webpage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teams are responsible for dividing their workload. Except under extreme circumstances, all members of the team will receive the same grade for each project. One member of each team is designated the leader. The files for each project should be zipped up and uploaded by the team leader using Canvas before the due date. Projects must not be stored in a public folder. All project submissions must follow the provided file name requirements or risk a score of 0. &lt;strong&gt;If the project does not compile, the student will receive a score of 0.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Projects will be graded based on the following criteria:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Correctness: Finding the right answer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Formatting:	Displaying the right answer according to instructions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Style and Documentation: Producing readable code with appropriate comments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, projects will be graded with the &lt;em&gt;diff&lt;/em&gt; utility. For that reason, it is imperative that project output matches sample output to the character.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Late assignment will lose &lt;img src=&#34;https://latex.codecogs.com/png.latex?%5Cdpi%7B150%7D%20%5Cfn_phv%20%5Clarge%202%5E%7B%28n-1%29%7D&#34; alt=&#34;equation&#34;&gt; points per day, including weekends and holidays. For example, -1 after 1 day, -2 after 2 days, -4 after 3 days … until 8+ days students will receive 0 score.  Under no circumstances should any student disclose their code, or copy the code written by other students or from an outside source. Both students will receive 0 score on the disclosed/copied assignment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-class-labs&#34;&gt;In-class Labs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All labs are to be done individually, in class, with the assistance of the instructor. Each assignment will be given near the beginning of a class and must be uploaded to Canvas (&lt;a href=&#34;https://etown.instructure.com/&#34;&gt;https://etown.instructure.com/&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;code&gt;before the end of the class without late penalty&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;code&gt;Extended submission is due on the same day before midnight, but any submission during this grace period will receive 15 points (out of 100) of late penalty&lt;/code&gt;. Submissions beyond midnight the same day will not be accepted.
To receive full credit, a programming assignment must compile, but partial credit will be awarded based on the understanding of the material demonstrated by the student’s code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grading Policies</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs222/grading/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs222/grading/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;grading-weights&#34;&gt;Grading Weights&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final grade for this course depends upon the grades and scores earned on course components weighted as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;24%&lt;/strong&gt;: 3 equally weighted projects – 8% for each project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;24%&lt;/strong&gt;: 8 equally weighted in-class labs – 3% for each lab.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5%&lt;/strong&gt; : Pop quizzes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2%&lt;/strong&gt; : Persistence. Including attendance and in-class question answering.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;25%&lt;/strong&gt;: 2 midterm exams - 10% for the lower grade, and 15% for the higher grade.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20%&lt;/strong&gt;: Final exam.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grades will be computed by rounding numerical percentages to the nearest integer and applying the following table:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Letter&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Range&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Letter&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Range&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Letter&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Range&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;93-100&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;80-82&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;67-69&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;90-92&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;77-79&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;63-66&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;87-89&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;73-76&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;60-62&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;83-86&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;70-72&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0-59&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-Note&#34;&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;projects&#34;&gt;Projects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All projects are team projects in this course. For each project, all students must form teams of two (or three in the case of an odd number of students). Students are permitted to select their own teams; however, no two students may partner up for more than one project. In other words, each team will be different for each project. Students should select their teams by using the Groups tab under People, on the Canvas webpage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teams are responsible for dividing their workload. Except under extreme circumstances, all members of the team will receive the same grade for each project. One member of each team is designated the leader. The files for each project should be zipped up and uploaded by the team leader using Canvas before the due date. Projects must not be stored in a public folder. All project submissions must follow the provided file name requirements or risk a score of 0. &lt;strong&gt;If the project does not compile, the student will receive a score of 0.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Projects will be graded based on the following criteria:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Correctness: Finding the right answer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Formatting:	Displaying the right answer according to instructions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Style and Documentation: Producing readable code with appropriate comments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, projects will be graded with the &lt;em&gt;diff&lt;/em&gt; utility. For that reason, it is imperative that project output matches sample output to the character.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Late assignment will lose &lt;img src=&#34;https://latex.codecogs.com/png.latex?%5Cdpi%7B150%7D%20%5Cfn_phv%20%5Clarge%202%5E%7B%28n-1%29%7D&#34; alt=&#34;equation&#34;&gt; points per day, including weekends and holidays. For example, -1 after 1 day, -2 after 2 days, -4 after 3 days … until 8+ days students will receive 0 score.  &lt;strong&gt;Under no circumstances should any student disclose their code, or copy the code written by other students or from an outside source. Both students will receive 0 score on the disclosed/copied assignment.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-class-labs&#34;&gt;In-class Labs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All labs are to be done in class, with the assistance of the instructor. Each assignment will be given near the beginning of a class and must be uploaded to Canvas (&lt;a href=&#34;https://etown.instructure.com/&#34;&gt;https://etown.instructure.com/&lt;/a&gt;) before the end of the class. Exercises submitted after class is over will not be accepted. To receive full credit, a programming assignment must compile, but partial credit will be awarded based on the understanding of the material demonstrated by the student’s code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grading Policies</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs400/grading/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs400/grading/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;grading-weights&#34;&gt;Grading Weights&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final grade for this course depends upon the grades and scores earned on course components weighted as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20%&lt;/strong&gt;: Project proposal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10%&lt;/strong&gt;: Milestone 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10%&lt;/strong&gt;: Milestone 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10%&lt;/strong&gt;: Milestone 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;30%&lt;/strong&gt;: Final project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20%&lt;/strong&gt;: Final paper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grades will be computed by rounding numerical percentages to the nearest integer and applying the following table:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Letter&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Range&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Letter&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Range&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Letter&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Range&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;93-100&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;80-82&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;67-69&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;90-92&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;77-79&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;63-66&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;87-89&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;73-76&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;60-62&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;83-86&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;70-72&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0-59&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grades for the proposal, milestones, final project, and final paper will be recorded in Canvas (&lt;a href=&#34;https://etown.instructure.com/)&#34;&gt;https://etown.instructure.com/)&lt;/a&gt;. Students may compute their current average by using these scores with the weights listed above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;proposal&#34;&gt;Proposal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All work is individual in this course. Each student, working with the instructor, will formulate the outline of a project. The plan for this project including goals should be written up and presented as a formal proposal due on the date specified in the course schedule. It should be turned in as a Word, LaTex, or PDF file and uploaded into Canvas before 11:59pm on the due day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;milestones&#34;&gt;Milestones&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the project has been proposed and approved, each student will have to present a document and give an oral presentation for each of three milestones. The document should be turned in as a Word, LaTeX, or PDF file. This document should be included in a zip file that also contains appropriate code. This zip file should be uploaded into Canvas before 11:59pm on the due date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Milestone&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Content&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Required hardware and software&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Desired features&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Expected timeline&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Implementation of essential features&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Working code&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Evidence of good software engineering and design&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Final features (no features should be added after Milestone 3)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Testing and debugging plan&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;final-project-and-paper&#34;&gt;Final Project and Paper&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A working version of the source code will be submitted by compressing it in a zip file and uploading that file onto Canvas before 11:59pm on the final project due date. Likewise, a paper of at least 8 pages (2,000 words) describing the purpose of the project, previous work done in the area, implementation details, successes, failures, and potential future work should be submitted. It should be turned in as a Word, LaTex, or PDF file and uploaded into Canvas before 11:59pm on the final project due date.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grading Policies</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs495/grading/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs495/grading/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;grading-weights&#34;&gt;Grading Weights&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final grade for this course depends upon the grades and scores earned on course components weighted as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20%&lt;/strong&gt;: Project proposal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10%&lt;/strong&gt;: Milestone 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10%&lt;/strong&gt;: Milestone 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10%&lt;/strong&gt;: Milestone 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;30%&lt;/strong&gt;: Final project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20%&lt;/strong&gt;: Final paper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grades will be computed by rounding numerical percentages to the nearest integer and applying the following table:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Letter&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Range&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Letter&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Range&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Letter&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Range&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;93-100&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;80-82&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;67-69&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;90-92&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;77-79&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;63-66&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;87-89&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;73-76&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;60-62&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;83-86&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;70-72&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0-59&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grades for the proposal, milestones, final project, and final paper will be recorded in Canvas (&lt;a href=&#34;https://etown.instructure.com/)&#34;&gt;https://etown.instructure.com/)&lt;/a&gt;. Students may compute their current average by using these scores with the weights listed above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;proposal&#34;&gt;Proposal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All work is individual in this course. Each student, working with the instructor, will formulate the outline of a project. The plan for this project including goals should be written up and presented as a formal proposal due on the date specified in the course schedule. It should be turned in as a Word, LaTex, or PDF file and uploaded into Canvas before 11:59pm on the due day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;milestones&#34;&gt;Milestones&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the project has been proposed and approved, each student will have to present a document and give an oral presentation for each of three milestones. The document should be turned in as a Word, LaTeX, or PDF file. This document should be included in a zip file that also contains appropriate code. This zip file should be uploaded into Canvas before 11:59pm on the due date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Milestone&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Content&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Required hardware and software&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Desired features&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Expected timeline&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Implementation of essential features&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Working code&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Evidence of good software engineering and design&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Final features (no features should be added after Milestone 3)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Testing and debugging plan&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;final-project-and-paper&#34;&gt;Final Project and Paper&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A working version of the source code will be submitted by compressing it in a zip file and uploading that file onto Canvas before 11:59pm on the final project due date. Likewise, a paper of at least 8 pages (2,000 words) describing the purpose of the project, previous work done in the area, implementation details, successes, failures, and potential future work should be submitted. It should be turned in as a Word, LaTex, or PDF file and uploaded into Canvas before 11:59pm on the final project due date.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grading Policies</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/ds200/grading/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/ds200/grading/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;grading-weights&#34;&gt;Grading Weights&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final grade for this course depends upon the grades and scores earned on course components weighted as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;24%&lt;/strong&gt;: 8 equally weighted in-class labs - 4% for each lab.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20%&lt;/strong&gt;: 5 equally weighted homework assignments – 4% for each assignment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;25%&lt;/strong&gt;: 2 midterm exams - 10% for lower grade, and 15% for higher grade.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2%&lt;/strong&gt; : Persistence. In-class question answering and attendance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6%&lt;/strong&gt; : Pop quizzes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8%&lt;/strong&gt; : Paper Presentation - peer evaluation (50%), instructor evaluation (50%).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;15%&lt;/strong&gt;: Final Project - project proposal (10%). Midterm check (10%). Project demonstration and presentation (40%). Final project report and revised code (40%).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grades will be computed by rounding numerical percentages to the nearest integer and applying the following table:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Letter&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Range&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Letter&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Range&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Letter&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Range&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;93-100&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;80-82&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;67-69&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;90-92&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;77-79&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;63-66&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;87-89&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;73-76&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;60-62&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;83-86&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;70-72&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0-59&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-Note&#34;&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;homework-assignments&#34;&gt;Homework Assignments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All homework assignments have to be completed individually in this course. Each assignment must be uploaded into Canvas (&lt;a href=&#34;https://etown.instructure.com/)&#34;&gt;https://etown.instructure.com/)&lt;/a&gt;.  Assignments must &lt;em&gt;NOT&lt;/em&gt; be stored in a public folder. All submissions must follow the provided file name requirements or risk a score of 0.&lt;br&gt;
Typically, you will have about two weeks to complete each assignment. All assignments will be graded based on the following criteria:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Correctness: Finding the right answer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Formatting:	Displaying the right answer according to instructions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Style and Documentation: Producing readable code with appropriate comments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Late assignment will lose &lt;img src=&#34;https://latex.codecogs.com/png.latex?%5Cdpi%7B150%7D%20%5Cfn_phv%20%5Clarge%202%5E%7B%28n-1%29%7D&#34; alt=&#34;equation&#34;&gt; points per day, including weekends and holidays. For example, -1 after 1 day, -2 after 2 days, -4 after 3 days … until 8+ days students will receive 0 score.  Under no circumstances should any student disclose their code, or copy the code written by other students or from an outside source. Both students will receive 0 score on the disclosed/copied assignment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-class-labs&#34;&gt;In-class labs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All labs are to be completed individually in class, with the assistance of the instructor.  Each lab will be given near the beginning of a class and must be uploaded to Canvas (&lt;a href=&#34;https://etown.instructure.com/&#34;&gt;https://etown.instructure.com/&lt;/a&gt;) before the end of the class.  Exercises submitted after class is over will not be accepted.  To receive full credit, the source code must be well commented and executed without errors, but partial credit will be considered by the instructor based on the understanding of the material demonstrated by the student’s code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;technical-paper-presentation&#34;&gt;Technical Paper Presentation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presenting data analysis results to public is one of the highly demanded skills from data science employers. As part of the final grade of this course, students are required to read one to two technical papers from the provided paper list (or other papers agreed by the instructor), and present the paper during the last week of class. The grading of the paper presentation consists of 50% from peers and 50% from the instructor. The evaluation rubrics will be provided via Canvas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;final-project&#34;&gt;Final Project&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final project best demonstrates students’ understanding of the lecture contents and their capability of solving real data science problems. Students are encouraged to form teams of no more than 2 people. Solo projects are also allowed if having good reasons. Topics of the final project are left open for the teams to find, but the final choice has to be decided upon the instructor’s agreement. A good list of potential projects can be found at Kaggle (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kaggle.com/datasets&#34;&gt;https://www.kaggle.com/datasets&lt;/a&gt;) and here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/awesomedata/awesome-public-datasets&#34;&gt;https://github.com/awesomedata/awesome-public-datasets&lt;/a&gt;. Teams are responsible for finding the project of their interest and discussing the project feasibility face-to-face with the project manager, a.k.a., the instructor 1 week before the project proposal is due. Project formation is on a rolling basis, meaning formerly finalized projects cannot be taken again by another team. The grading of the final project consists of four major aspects:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10%: the project proposal (including the conversation with the instructor a week before due);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10%: mid-term project check (must have shown substantial exploratory data analysis);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;40%: the project demonstration; code and slides are due the night before the presentation day;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;40%: everything including report; revised code and the report are due on Friday of the final week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The requirements and grading rubric for each component of the project will be posted on Canvas. Under no circumstances should any student copy the code from an outside source. Source code similarity tools will be used to detect plagiarism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;There is a potential pitfall of using open datasets to introduce data science that some students want to leverage.  I want to be crystal clear that the point of this project is to learn as much as possible. The point of this project is not to achieve the most intriguing results on the Kaggle leaderboard. For instance, if you copied some code you didn&#39;t understand and used it to get very compelling analytical results, I would consider this a very poor project.  However, if you thoughtfully try various strategies, incorporate lots of interesting learning resources, and do a good job communicating with your peers regarding what worked and what didn&#39;t, I would consider that highly successful even if your results were not the best.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grading Policies</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/ds300/grading/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/ds300/grading/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;grading-weights&#34;&gt;Grading Weights&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final grade for this course depends upon the grades and scores earned on course components weighted as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;32%&lt;/strong&gt;: 8 equally weighted in-class labs - 4% for each lab.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20%&lt;/strong&gt;: 5 equally weighted homework assignments – 4% for each assignment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;25%&lt;/strong&gt;: 2 midterm exams - 10% for lower grade, and 15% for higher grade.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3%&lt;/strong&gt; : Pop quizzes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5%&lt;/strong&gt; : Paper Presentation - peer evaluation (50%), instructor evaluation (50%).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;15%&lt;/strong&gt;: Final Project - project proposal (10%). Midterm check (10%). Project demonstration and presentation (40%). Final project report and revised code (40%).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grades will be computed by rounding numerical percentages to the nearest integer and applying the following table:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Letter&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Range&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Letter&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Range&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Letter&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Range&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;93-100&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;80-82&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;67-69&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;90-92&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;77-79&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;63-66&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;87-89&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;73-76&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;60-62&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;83-86&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;70-72&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0-59&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-Note&#34;&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;homework-assignments&#34;&gt;Homework Assignments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All homework assignments have to be completed individually in this course. Each assignment must be uploaded into Canvas (&lt;a href=&#34;https://etown.instructure.com/)&#34;&gt;https://etown.instructure.com/)&lt;/a&gt;.  Assignments must &lt;em&gt;NOT&lt;/em&gt; be stored in a public folder. All submissions must follow the provided file name requirements or risk a score of 0.&lt;br&gt;
Typically, you will have about two weeks to complete each assignment. All assignments will be graded based on the following criteria:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Correctness: Finding the right answer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Formatting:	Displaying the right answer according to instructions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Style and Documentation: Producing readable code with appropriate comments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Late assignment will lose &lt;img src=&#34;https://latex.codecogs.com/png.latex?%5Cdpi%7B150%7D%20%5Cfn_phv%20%5Clarge%202%5E%7B%28n-1%29%7D&#34; alt=&#34;equation&#34;&gt; points per day, including weekends and holidays. For example, -1 after 1 day, -2 after 2 days, -4 after 3 days … until 8+ days students will receive 0 score.  Under no circumstances should any student disclose their code, or copy the code written by other students or from an outside source. Both students will receive 0 score on the disclosed/copied assignment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-class-labs&#34;&gt;In-class labs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All labs are to be done individually, in class, with the assistance of the instructor. Each assignment will be given near the beginning of a class and must be uploaded to Canvas (&lt;a href=&#34;https://etown.instructure.com/&#34;&gt;https://etown.instructure.com/&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;code&gt;before the end of the class without late penalty&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;code&gt;Extended submission is due on the same day before midnight, but any submission during this grace period will receive 15 points (out of 100) of late penalty&lt;/code&gt;. Submissions beyond midnight the same day will not be accepted. To receive full credit, the source code must be well commented and executed without errors, but partial credit will be considered by the instructor based on the understanding of the material demonstrated by the student’s code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;technical-paper-presentation&#34;&gt;Technical Paper Presentation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presenting data analysis results to public is one of the highly demanded skills from data science employers. As part of the final grade of this course, students are required to read one to two technical papers from the provided paper list (or other papers agreed by the instructor), and present the paper during the last week of class. The grading of the paper presentation consists of 50% from peers and 50% from the instructor. The evaluation rubrics will be provided via Canvas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;final-project&#34;&gt;Final Project&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final project best demonstrates students’ understanding of the lecture contents and their capability of solving real data science problems. Students are encouraged to form teams of no more than 2 people. Solo projects are also allowed if having good reasons. Topics of the final project are left open for the teams to find, but the final choice has to be decided upon the instructor’s agreement. A good list of potential projects can be found at UCI Machine Learning Repository (&lt;a href=&#34;http://archive.ics.uci.edu/ml),&#34;&gt;http://archive.ics.uci.edu/ml),&lt;/a&gt; Kaggle (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kaggle.com/datasets&#34;&gt;https://www.kaggle.com/datasets&lt;/a&gt;) and here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/awesomedata/awesome-public-datasets&#34;&gt;https://github.com/awesomedata/awesome-public-datasets&lt;/a&gt;. Teams are responsible for finding the project of their interest and discussing the project feasibility face-to-face with the project manager, a.k.a., the instructor 1 week before the project proposal is due. Project formation is on a rolling basis, meaning formerly finalized projects cannot be taken again by another team. The grading of the final project consists of four major aspects:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10%: the project proposal (including the conversation with the instructor a week before due);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10%: mid-term project check (must have shown substantial exploratory data analysis);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;40%: the project demonstration; code and slides are due the night before the presentation day;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;40%: everything including report; revised code and the report are due on Friday of the final week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The requirements and grading rubric for each component of the project will be posted on Canvas. Under no circumstances should any student copy the code from an outside source. Source code similarity tools will be used to detect plagiarism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;There is a potential pitfall of using open datasets to introduce data science that some students want to leverage.  I want to be crystal clear that the point of this project is to learn as much as possible. The point of this project is not to achieve the most intriguing results on the Kaggle leaderboard. For instance, if you copied some code you didn&#39;t understand and used it to get very compelling analytical results, I would consider this a very poor project.  However, if you thoughtfully try various strategies, incorporate lots of interesting learning resources, and do a good job communicating with your peers regarding what worked and what didn&#39;t, I would consider that highly successful even if your results were not the best.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grading Policies</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/ds420/grading/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/ds420/grading/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;grading-weights&#34;&gt;Grading Weights&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final grade for this course depends upon the grades and scores earned on course components weighted as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;30%&lt;/strong&gt;: 6 equally weighted in-class labs - 5% for each lab.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20%&lt;/strong&gt;: 5 equally weighted homework assignments – 4% for each assignment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;25%&lt;/strong&gt;: 2 midterm exams - 10% for lower grade, and 15% for higher grade.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5%&lt;/strong&gt; : Pop quizzes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5%&lt;/strong&gt; : Paper Presentation - peer evaluation (50%), instructor evaluation (50%).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;15%&lt;/strong&gt;: Final Project - project proposal (10%). Midterm check (10%). Project demonstration and presentation (40%). Final project report and revised code (40%).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grades will be computed by rounding numerical percentages to the nearest integer and applying the following table:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Letter&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Range&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Letter&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Range&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Letter&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Range&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;93-100&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;80-82&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;67-69&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;90-92&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;77-79&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;63-66&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;87-89&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;73-76&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;60-62&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;83-86&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;70-72&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0-59&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-Grades&#34;&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;homework-assignments&#34;&gt;Homework Assignments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All homework assignments have to be completed individually in this course. Each assignment must be uploaded into Canvas (&lt;a href=&#34;https://etown.instructure.com/)&#34;&gt;https://etown.instructure.com/)&lt;/a&gt;.  Assignments must &lt;em&gt;NOT&lt;/em&gt; be stored in a public folder. All submissions must follow the provided file name requirements or risk a score of 0.&lt;br&gt;
Typically, you will have about two weeks to complete each assignment. All assignments will be graded based on the following criteria:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Correctness: Finding the right answer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Formatting:	Displaying the right answer according to instructions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Style and Documentation: Producing readable code with appropriate comments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Late assignment will lose &lt;img src=&#34;https://latex.codecogs.com/png.latex?%5Cdpi%7B150%7D%20%5Cfn_phv%20%5Clarge%202%5E%7B%28n-1%29%7D&#34; alt=&#34;equation&#34;&gt; points per day, including weekends and holidays. For example, -1 after 1 day, -2 after 2 days, -4 after 3 days … until 8+ days students will receive 0 score.  Under no circumstances should any student disclose their code, or copy the code written by other students or from an outside source. Both students will receive 0 score on the disclosed/copied assignment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-class-labs&#34;&gt;In-class labs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All labs are to be done individually, in class, with the assistance of the instructor. Each assignment will be given near the beginning of a class and must be uploaded to Canvas (&lt;a href=&#34;https://etown.instructure.com/&#34;&gt;https://etown.instructure.com/&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;code&gt;before the end of the class without late penalty&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;code&gt;Extended submission is due on the same day before midnight, but any submission during this grace period will receive 15 points (out of 100) of late penalty&lt;/code&gt;. Submissions beyond midnight the same day will not be accepted. To receive full credit, the source code must be well commented and executed without errors, but partial credit will be considered by the instructor based on the understanding of the material demonstrated by the student’s code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;technical-paper-presentation&#34;&gt;Technical Paper Presentation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presenting data analysis results to public is one of the highly demanded skills from data science employers. As part of the final grade of this course, students are required to read one to two technical papers from the provided paper list (or other papers agreed by the instructor), and present the paper during the last week of class. The grading of the paper presentation consists of 50% from peers and 50% from the instructor. The evaluation rubrics will be provided via Canvas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;final-project&#34;&gt;Final Project&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final project best demonstrates students’ understanding of the lecture contents and their capability of solving data science problems as a team or individually. The topic of the final project is left open for the students to solicitate, but the final choice has to be decided upon the instructor’s agreement.
Students are allowed to form a team of no more than 2 people. Teams are responsible for finding the project of their interest and discussing the project feasibility face-to-face with the project manager, a.k.a., the instructor 1 week before the proposal is due. Since the teams have to work on different project topics, the finalization of the project title is on a rolling basis – meaning formerly finalized projects cannot be taken again by another team. The deliverable of the final project contains four major components:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10%: the project proposal: must be approved by the instructor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10%: midterm check: must have finished essential literature search and data cleaning at this point&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;40%: the project verbal and visual demonstration in class: code and slides must be uploaded the day before the presentation day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;40%: the project report: due on Wed of the Final Exam week. Must be completed and have included the instructor&#39;s improvement suggestions in the final version.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The requirements and grading rubric for each component of the project will be posted on Canvas. Under no circumstances should any student copy the code from an outside source. Source code similarity tools will be used to detect plagiarism.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grading Policies</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/ds495/grading/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/ds495/grading/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;grading-weights&#34;&gt;Grading Weights&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final grade for this course depends upon the grades and scores earned on course components weighted as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20%&lt;/strong&gt;: Project proposal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10%&lt;/strong&gt;: Milestone 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10%&lt;/strong&gt;: Milestone 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10%&lt;/strong&gt;: Milestone 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;30%&lt;/strong&gt;: Final project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20%&lt;/strong&gt;: Final paper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grades will be computed by rounding numerical percentages to the nearest integer and applying the following table:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Letter&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Range&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Letter&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Range&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Letter&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Range&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;93-100&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;80-82&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;67-69&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;90-92&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;77-79&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;63-66&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;87-89&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;73-76&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;60-62&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;83-86&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;70-72&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0-59&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grades for the proposal, milestones, final project, and final paper will be recorded in Canvas (&lt;a href=&#34;https://etown.instructure.com/)&#34;&gt;https://etown.instructure.com/)&lt;/a&gt;. Students may compute their current average by using these scores with the weights listed above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;proposal&#34;&gt;Proposal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All work is individual in this course. Each student, working with the instructor, will formulate the outline of a project. The plan for this project including goals should be written up and presented as a formal proposal due on the date specified in the course schedule. It should be turned in as a Word, LaTex, or PDF file and uploaded into Canvas before 11:59pm on the due day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;milestones&#34;&gt;Milestones&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the project has been proposed and approved, each student will have to &lt;code&gt;present a document and give an oral presentation&lt;/code&gt; for &lt;code&gt;each of three milestones&lt;/code&gt;. The document should be turned in as a Word, LaTeX, or PDF file. This document should be included in a zip file that also contains appropriate code. This zip file should be uploaded into Canvas before 11:59pm on the due date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Milestone&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Content&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Dataset collection, preprocessing, and exploratory data analysis&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Models to be implemented and results to be presented&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Expected timeline&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Continued exploratory data analysis with visuals for demo&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Feature study and feature extraction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Model implementation and scoring&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Parameter tuning to obtain optimal model performance&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Final application design with detailed use cases&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Models comparison within the project and with literatures&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Future works&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;final-project-and-paper&#34;&gt;Final Project and Paper&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A working version of the source code will be submitted by compressing it in a zip file and uploading that file onto Canvas before 11:59pm on the final project due date. Likewise, a paper of at least 8 pages (2,000 words) describing the purpose of the project, previous work done in the area, implementation details, successes, failures, and potential future work should be submitted. It should be turned in as a Word, LaTex, or PDF file and uploaded into Canvas before 11:59pm on the final project due date.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grading Rubrics</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/ds200/rubrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/ds200/rubrics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;code&#34;&gt;Code&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grading rubrics for code submission in terms of percentage:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;100&#34;&gt;100%:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Functionality: For assignments that have well-specified behavior, the code should be able to pass (or very nearly pass, e.g. there may be minor output formatting issues) automated unit testing of all required features. For open-ended assignments the code must be easy to run without modification and implement all of the required functionality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation: all functions are commented with appropriate doc strings. For open-ended assignments there is a README file discussing how to run the program and what it is supposed to do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Style: the program exhibits effective modular design. The code does not have unnecessary cut and paste code or magic numbers. Variable and function names are sensibly chosen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;80&#34;&gt;80%:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Functionality: For assignments that have well-specified behavior, the code should implement all of the required functionality. For this grade, it is possible that 10-20% of the functionality may be broken. For open-ended assignments it will be possible to get the code running with modest effort (i.e. it will not be as well documented as in a 5, but it isn’t too hard to intuit how the code works). For these types of assignments all required features must be present, however, some (10-20%) may not be functioning properly or otherwise poorly implemented.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation: some functions are missing doc strings. Comments are fairly minimal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Style: some aspects of the design of the program could be improved to reduce cut and paste code. Variable and function names are for the most part well-chosen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;60&#34;&gt;60%:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Functionality: The code should implement almost all of the required features (it is okay if roughly 20% are not implemented). A significant portion, 30-50%, of the code may not work as it is supposed to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation: Docstrings are mostly absent For well-defined assignments the code does not run as it should based on the assignment spec. For open-ended assignments there may not be any indication of how to run the program, and it is not easy for a NINJA to figure out how the code works (a good test is if you have to e-mail someone to ask them how their code runs, they are probably at this level).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Style: the program design needs improvement. The code would be a lot cleaner if the author had done a better job thinking through the appropriate functional decomposition. The code has lots of cut and paste and magic numbers. Variable and function names are hard to interpret.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;40&#34;&gt;40%:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Functionality: the assignment is incomplete (~50% of the functionality is not implemented). The functionality that is implemented is not 100% correct.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation: mostly absent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Style: design is poor. Very little attention has been paid to choosing a sensible functional decomposition.  Variable and function names are chosen almost arbitrarily.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;20&#34;&gt;20%:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Functionality: only minimal functionality is present.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation: little or none.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Style: Code is not “readable”. Poor choice of variable and function names.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;0&#34;&gt;0%:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;nothing turned in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;notebook-assignments&#34;&gt;Notebook Assignments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jupyter notebooks are the files you need to submit for labs and homework assignments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;100-1&#34;&gt;100%:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thorough engagement with each section of the reading.  Each exercise has either been completed, or you have articulated a well-thought out set of questions for each of the problems you didn&#39;t answer.
Points will be deducted from 100% for the following reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exercises are not filled out (either with a solution or a question)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The answer to the exercise does not demonstrate a good faith attempt to complete it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;writing&#34;&gt;Writing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing will be evaluated for clarity, concision, and comprehensiveness.  The particular style that you should use will depend on the assignment and your audience.  The bottom line is don&#39;t cut corners with writing in this class.  Your ability to communicate what you have done is just as important as what you have done.  Don&#39;t make the mistake of spending all of your time writing code, and then rush through the writing parts of the assignment.  See below for some stylistic guidance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Since the dawn of time, college students have been writing introductions that are too grandiose (and often false).  Just get into it; you don&#39;t have to zoom in from space (and make stuff up).  Write the abstract last and summarize the most important result.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The passive voice is a hoax. Please write in the first person (singular or plural).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write in the present tense whenever possible.  Some actions happen in the past, but all research exists in an eternal present: &amp;ldquo;Using data from BRFSS, they plot weight versus height and find that tall respondents are heavier, on average, than shorter respondents.  Our results are consistent with this conclusion.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you edit, try to remove words.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid using &amp;ldquo;significant&amp;rdquo; unless you mean &amp;ldquo;statistically significant;&amp;rdquo; a good alternative is &amp;ldquo;substantial.&amp;rdquo;  Avoid using &amp;ldquo;correlation&amp;rdquo; unless you mean a coefficient of correlation.  In general, there might be a &amp;ldquo;relationship&amp;rdquo; between variables and you might characterize it with a correlation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Trend&amp;rdquo; usually means something is changing in time; &amp;ldquo;pattern&amp;rdquo; is more general.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide indicators of logical flow.  If I ask you to answer a set of question in your report, don&#39;t just paste the questions as your section headings.  You should create your own document structure based on what makes sense for your project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explain your motivation.  Avoid &amp;ldquo;We were interested&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;We wanted&amp;rdquo; as pseudo-motivation.  And don&#39;t look at the camera; that is, don&#39;t use &amp;ldquo;because we were told to&amp;rdquo; as motivation, and avoid &amp;ldquo;for this project&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you refer to figures and tables, capitalize &amp;ldquo;Figure&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Table.&amp;rdquo;  Formal figures have a number and a caption, and they can float.  Informal figures are part of the text flow.  If a figure doesn&#39;t contain much information, summarize it in text.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find an authorial voice that is casual enough to be engaging (without overdoing it).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grading Rubrics</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/ds300/rubrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/ds300/rubrics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;code&#34;&gt;Code&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grading rubrics for code submission in terms of percentage:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;100&#34;&gt;100%:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Functionality: For assignments that have well-specified behavior, the code should be able to pass (or very nearly pass, e.g. there may be minor output formatting issues) automated unit testing of all required features. For open-ended assignments the code must be easy to run without modification and implement all of the required functionality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation: all functions are commented with appropriate doc strings. For open-ended assignments there is a README file discussing how to run the program and what it is supposed to do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Style: the program exhibits effective modular design. The code does not have unnecessary cut and paste code or magic numbers. Variable and function names are sensibly chosen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;80&#34;&gt;80%:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Functionality: For assignments that have well-specified behavior, the code should implement all of the required functionality. For this grade, it is possible that 10-20% of the functionality may be broken. For open-ended assignments it will be possible to get the code running with modest effort (i.e. it will not be as well documented as in a 5, but it isn’t too hard to intuit how the code works). For these types of assignments all required features must be present, however, some (10-20%) may not be functioning properly or otherwise poorly implemented.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation: some functions are missing doc strings. Comments are fairly minimal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Style: some aspects of the design of the program could be improved to reduce cut and paste code. Variable and function names are for the most part well-chosen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;60&#34;&gt;60%:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Functionality: The code should implement almost all of the required features (it is okay if roughly 20% are not implemented). A significant portion, 30-50%, of the code may not work as it is supposed to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation: Docstrings are mostly absent For well-defined assignments the code does not run as it should based on the assignment spec. For open-ended assignments there may not be any indication of how to run the program, and it is not easy for a NINJA to figure out how the code works (a good test is if you have to e-mail someone to ask them how their code runs, they are probably at this level).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Style: the program design needs improvement. The code would be a lot cleaner if the author had done a better job thinking through the appropriate functional decomposition. The code has lots of cut and paste and magic numbers. Variable and function names are hard to interpret.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;40&#34;&gt;40%:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Functionality: the assignment is incomplete (~50% of the functionality is not implemented). The functionality that is implemented is not 100% correct.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation: mostly absent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Style: design is poor. Very little attention has been paid to choosing a sensible functional decomposition.  Variable and function names are chosen almost arbitrarily.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;20&#34;&gt;20%:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Functionality: only minimal functionality is present.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation: little or none.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Style: Code is not “readable”. Poor choice of variable and function names.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;0&#34;&gt;0%:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;nothing turned in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;notebook-assignments&#34;&gt;Notebook Assignments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jupyter notebooks are the files you need to submit for labs and homework assignments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;100-1&#34;&gt;100%:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thorough engagement with each section of the reading.  Each exercise has either been completed, or you have articulated a well-thought out set of questions for each of the problems you didn&#39;t answer.
Points will be deducted from 100% for the following reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exercises are not filled out (either with a solution or a question)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The answer to the exercise does not demonstrate a good faith attempt to complete it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;writing&#34;&gt;Writing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing will be evaluated for clarity, concision, and comprehensiveness.  The particular style that you should use will depend on the assignment and your audience.  The bottom line is don&#39;t cut corners with writing in this class.  Your ability to communicate what you have done is just as important as what you have done.  Don&#39;t make the mistake of spending all of your time writing code, and then rush through the writing parts of the assignment.  See below for some stylistic guidance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Since the dawn of time, college students have been writing introductions that are too grandiose (and often false).  Just get into it; you don&#39;t have to zoom in from space (and make stuff up).  Write the abstract last and summarize the most important result.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The passive voice is a hoax. Please write in the first person (singular or plural).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write in the present tense whenever possible.  Some actions happen in the past, but all research exists in an eternal present: &amp;ldquo;Using data from BRFSS, they plot weight versus height and find that tall respondents are heavier, on average, than shorter respondents.  Our results are consistent with this conclusion.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you edit, try to remove words.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid using &amp;ldquo;significant&amp;rdquo; unless you mean &amp;ldquo;statistically significant;&amp;rdquo; a good alternative is &amp;ldquo;substantial.&amp;rdquo;  Avoid using &amp;ldquo;correlation&amp;rdquo; unless you mean a coefficient of correlation.  In general, there might be a &amp;ldquo;relationship&amp;rdquo; between variables and you might characterize it with a correlation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Trend&amp;rdquo; usually means something is changing in time; &amp;ldquo;pattern&amp;rdquo; is more general.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide indicators of logical flow.  If I ask you to answer a set of question in your report, don&#39;t just paste the questions as your section headings.  You should create your own document structure based on what makes sense for your project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explain your motivation.  Avoid &amp;ldquo;We were interested&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;We wanted&amp;rdquo; as pseudo-motivation.  And don&#39;t look at the camera; that is, don&#39;t use &amp;ldquo;because we were told to&amp;rdquo; as motivation, and avoid &amp;ldquo;for this project&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you refer to figures and tables, capitalize &amp;ldquo;Figure&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Table.&amp;rdquo;  Formal figures have a number and a caption, and they can float.  Informal figures are part of the text flow.  If a figure doesn&#39;t contain much information, summarize it in text.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find an authorial voice that is casual enough to be engaging (without overdoing it).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grading Rubrics</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/ds420/rubrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/ds420/rubrics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;code&#34;&gt;Code&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grading rubrics for code submission in terms of percentage:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;100&#34;&gt;100%:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Functionality: For assignments that have well-specified behavior, the code should be able to pass (or very nearly pass, e.g. there may be minor output formatting issues) automated unit testing of all required features. For open-ended assignments the code must be easy to run without modification and implement all of the required functionality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation: all functions are commented with appropriate doc strings. For open-ended assignments there is a README file discussing how to run the program and what it is supposed to do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Style: the program exhibits effective modular design. The code does not have unnecessary cut and paste code or magic numbers. Variable and function names are sensibly chosen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;80&#34;&gt;80%:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Functionality: For assignments that have well-specified behavior, the code should implement all of the required functionality. For this grade, it is possible that 10-20% of the functionality may be broken. For open-ended assignments it will be possible to get the code running with modest effort (i.e. it will not be as well documented as in a 5, but it isn’t too hard to intuit how the code works). For these types of assignments all required features must be present, however, some (10-20%) may not be functioning properly or otherwise poorly implemented.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation: some functions are missing doc strings. Comments are fairly minimal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Style: some aspects of the design of the program could be improved to reduce cut and paste code. Variable and function names are for the most part well-chosen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;60&#34;&gt;60%:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Functionality: The code should implement almost all of the required features (it is okay if roughly 20% are not implemented). A significant portion, 30-50%, of the code may not work as it is supposed to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation: Docstrings are mostly absent For well-defined assignments the code does not run as it should based on the assignment spec. For open-ended assignments there may not be any indication of how to run the program, and it is not easy for a NINJA to figure out how the code works (a good test is if you have to e-mail someone to ask them how their code runs, they are probably at this level).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Style: the program design needs improvement. The code would be a lot cleaner if the author had done a better job thinking through the appropriate functional decomposition. The code has lots of cut and paste and magic numbers. Variable and function names are hard to interpret.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;40&#34;&gt;40%:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Functionality: the assignment is incomplete (~50% of the functionality is not implemented). The functionality that is implemented is not 100% correct.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation: mostly absent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Style: design is poor. Very little attention has been paid to choosing a sensible functional decomposition.  Variable and function names are chosen almost arbitrarily.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;20&#34;&gt;20%:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Functionality: only minimal functionality is present.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation: little or none.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Style: Code is not “readable”. Poor choice of variable and function names.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;0&#34;&gt;0%:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;nothing turned in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;notebook-assignments&#34;&gt;Notebook Assignments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jupyter notebooks are the files you need to submit for labs and homework assignments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;100-1&#34;&gt;100%:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thorough engagement with each section of the reading.  Each exercise has either been completed, or you have articulated a well-thought out set of questions for each of the problems you didn&#39;t answer.
Points will be deducted from 100% for the following reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exercises are not filled out (either with a solution or a question)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The answer to the exercise does not demonstrate a good faith attempt to complete it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;writing&#34;&gt;Writing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing will be evaluated for clarity, concision, and comprehensiveness.  The particular style that you should use will depend on the assignment and your audience.  The bottom line is don&#39;t cut corners with writing in this class.  Your ability to communicate what you have done is just as important as what you have done.  Don&#39;t make the mistake of spending all of your time writing code, and then rush through the writing parts of the assignment.  See below for some stylistic guidance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Since the dawn of time, college students have been writing introductions that are too grandiose (and often false).  Just get into it; you don&#39;t have to zoom in from space (and make stuff up).  Write the abstract last and summarize the most important result.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The passive voice is a hoax. Please write in the first person (singular or plural).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write in the present tense whenever possible.  Some actions happen in the past, but all research exists in an eternal present: &amp;ldquo;Using data from BRFSS, they plot weight versus height and find that tall respondents are heavier, on average, than shorter respondents.  Our results are consistent with this conclusion.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you edit, try to remove words.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid using &amp;ldquo;significant&amp;rdquo; unless you mean &amp;ldquo;statistically significant;&amp;rdquo; a good alternative is &amp;ldquo;substantial.&amp;rdquo;  Avoid using &amp;ldquo;correlation&amp;rdquo; unless you mean a coefficient of correlation.  In general, there might be a &amp;ldquo;relationship&amp;rdquo; between variables and you might characterize it with a correlation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Trend&amp;rdquo; usually means something is changing in time; &amp;ldquo;pattern&amp;rdquo; is more general.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide indicators of logical flow.  If I ask you to answer a set of question in your report, don&#39;t just paste the questions as your section headings.  You should create your own document structure based on what makes sense for your project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explain your motivation.  Avoid &amp;ldquo;We were interested&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;We wanted&amp;rdquo; as pseudo-motivation.  And don&#39;t look at the camera; that is, don&#39;t use &amp;ldquo;because we were told to&amp;rdquo; as motivation, and avoid &amp;ldquo;for this project&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you refer to figures and tables, capitalize &amp;ldquo;Figure&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Table.&amp;rdquo;  Formal figures have a number and a caption, and they can float.  Informal figures are part of the text flow.  If a figure doesn&#39;t contain much information, summarize it in text.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find an authorial voice that is casual enough to be engaging (without overdoing it).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Schedule</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs400/schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs400/schedule/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Note this tentative schedule is subject to change. Please check the schedule regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Week&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Starting&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Activities&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Notes&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1/13/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Research&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1/20/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Research&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1/27/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Research&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Proposal Due Mon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2/3/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Design&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2/10/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Design&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2/17/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Design&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Milestone 1 Due Mon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2/24/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Spring Break&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3/2/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Implementation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3/9/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Implementation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3/16/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Implementation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Milestone 2 Due Mon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3/23/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Implementation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3/30/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Implementation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;13&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4/6/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Implementation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Milestone 3 Due Mon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;14&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4/13/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Testing and Debugging&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;15&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4/20/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Testing and Debugging&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;16&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4/27/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Testing and Debugging&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Paper and Project Due&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Schedule</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs495/schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs495/schedule/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Note this tentative schedule is subject to change. Please check the schedule regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Week&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Starting&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Activities&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Notes&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8/24/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Literature search, Finalize topic with instructor&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mon: Start proposal&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8/31/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Proposal write-up&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9/7/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Overall design&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mon: Start Mileston 1, Proposal Due&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9/14/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Concrete feature design&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9/21/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Finalized design&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9/28/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Implementation 25%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mon: Start Mileston 2, Milestone 1 Due&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10/5/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Implementation 50%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10/12/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Implementation 75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10/19/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Implementation 100%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10/26/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Additional features&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mon: Start Mileston 3, Milestone 2 Due, mid-term demo during the week&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11/2/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Additional features&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11/9/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Write up testing and debugging plan&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;13&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11/16/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Final paper writeup, testing and debugging&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mon: Start final paper, Milestone 3 Due&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;14&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11/23/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Testing and debugging&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;15&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11/30/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Final presentation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Schedule a presentation time with instructor during the week&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;16&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;12/7/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Revise project with instructor feedback&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mon: Paper and Project Due&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Schedule</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/ds495/schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/ds495/schedule/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Note this tentative schedule is subject to change. Please check the schedule regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Week&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Starting&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Activities&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Notes&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8/24/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Literature search, Finalize topic with instructor&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mon: Start proposal&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8/31/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Proposal write-up&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9/7/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Data collection and preprocessing&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mon: Start Mileston 1, Proposal Due&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9/14/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Exploratory data analysis&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9/21/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Start model design&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9/28/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Feature extraction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mon: Start Mileston 2, Milestone 1 Due&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10/5/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Model implementation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10/12/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Model implementation and training&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10/19/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Parameter tuning&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10/26/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Application design and use cases&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mon: Start Mileston 3, Milestone 2 Due, mid-term demo during the week&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11/2/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Model evaluation and comparison&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11/9/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Final touch on the code&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;13&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11/16/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Final paper writeup&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mon: Start final paper, Milestone 3 Due&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;14&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11/23/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Code cleanup and packaging&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;15&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11/30/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Final presentation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Schedule a presentation time with instructor during the week&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;16&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;12/7/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Revise project with instructor feedback&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mon: Paper and Project Due&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proposal Requirements</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs400/proposal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs400/proposal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;specifications&#34;&gt;Specifications&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For details, please refer to &lt;a href=&#34;https://Peilong.github.io/files/cs400_495/cs400_495_proposal_guide.pdf&#34;&gt;Proposal Requirements&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proposal Requirements</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs495/proposal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs495/proposal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;specifications&#34;&gt;Specifications&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For details, please refer to &lt;a href=&#34;https://Peilong.github.io/files/cs400_495/cs400_495_proposal_guide.pdf&#34;&gt;Proposal Requirements&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proposal Requirements</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/ds495/proposal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/ds495/proposal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;specifications&#34;&gt;Specifications&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For details, please refer to &lt;a href=&#34;https://Peilong.github.io/files/ds495/ds495_proposal_guide.pdf&#34;&gt;Proposal Requirements&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Schedule</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs121/schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs121/schedule/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Note this tentative schedule is subject to change. Please check the schedule regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Week&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Starting&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Topics&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Reading&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Notes&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8/24/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Lec1 - Course introduction and overview&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SC Ch. 1 and 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Lec2 - Introduction to computer science&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TJ Ch. 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Lec3 - Software development &amp;amp; Lab 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8/31/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Lec4 - Data representation and data types&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SC Ch. 3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Lec5 -Math operations&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TJ Ch. 2 and 3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Lab 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9/7/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Lec6 - Boolean and character operations&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SC Ch. 3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Lec7 - Methods and string operations&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TJ Ch. 2, 3, 9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Lab 3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9/14/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Lec8 - Conditionals with if statements&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SC Ch. 4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mon: Project 1 out&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: PE1 - If statement coding exercise&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TJ Ch. 5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Lab 4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9/21/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Professional Development Day - No Classes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SC Ch. 5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Lec9 - Flowchart and debugging&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TJ Ch. 7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Lab 5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9/28/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Lec10 - While loops&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SC Ch. 5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Lec11 - Do-while loops&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TJ Ch. 7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Lec12 - For loops&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10/5/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: PE2 - Loops coding exercise&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SC Ch. 5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mon: Project 1 due, project 2 out&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Exam 1 preview&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TJ Ch. 7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Exam 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Exam 1 on Fri&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10/12/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Lab 6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SC Ch. 8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Lec13 - Static methods&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TJ Ch. 4, 6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Lec14 - Overloading methods&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10/19/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Lab test 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SC Ch. 6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Lab test 1 on Mon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Professional Development Day - No Classes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TJ Ch. 8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Lab 7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10/26/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Lec15 - 1D arrays&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SC Ch. 6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Lec16 - 2D arrays&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TJ Ch. 8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Lab 8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11/2/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Lec17 - Object oriented programming&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SC Ch. 9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mon: Project 2 due, project 3 out&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Lec18 - OOP classes and objects&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TJ Ch. 10, 11&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Lec19 - Object methods, accessors, mutators&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11/9/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: PE3 - OOP coding exercise&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TJ Ch. 12&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Lab 9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Lec20 - Algorithms&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;13&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11/16/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Lec21 - Searching algorithms&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TJ Ch. 13&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Lab 10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Lab test 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Lab test 2 on Fri&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;14&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11/23/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Exam 2 preview&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;All Notes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Thanksgiving - No Classes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Thanksgiving - No Classes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;15&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11/30/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Exam 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;All Notes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mon: Project 3 due, Exam 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Final exam QA&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Final exam QA&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;16&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;12/7/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Final Exam (11 AM - 2PM)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Schedule</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs222/schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs222/schedule/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Note this tentative schedule is subject to change. Please check the schedule regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Week&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Starting&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Topics&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Reading&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Notes&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1/13/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Course introduction and overview&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C: 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Basic C programming, Linux&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Linux: 1.1-1.2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: IDE Demo &amp;amp; Lab 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1/20/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: MLK Day, NO CLASS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C: 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No class on Mon (MLK Day)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Data types, operators, and printf&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Linux: 2.1-2.7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Console input with scanf, Compilation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1/27/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Conditionals: if and switch statements&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C: 3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: PE1 – Flowchart and Debugging&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Linux: 6.1-6.7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Lab 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2/3/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: While loops and do-while loops&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C: 3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: PE2 – conditionals and while loops&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Lab 3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2/10/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: For loops&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C: 4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Project 1 posted on Mon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Functions&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Lab 4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2/17/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Pointers and pointer arguments&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C: 5.1-5.5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Exam 1 on Friday&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: More on Pointers&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Exam 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2/24/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: PE3 – functions and pointers&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C: 5.6-5.12&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: One dimensional arrays&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: 2-D arrays; arrays with functions&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3/2/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Spring Break. NO CLASS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No class in the whole week&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Spring Break. NO CLASS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Spring Break. NO CLASS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3/9/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Character arrays and strings&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C: 6.1-6.4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Project 1 due on Mon midnight&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: String functions&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Class Canceled&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3/16/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Class Canceled&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C: 6.5-6.7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Project 2 posted on Mon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Lab 5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: C Structures&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3/23/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Nested structures&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.geeksforgeeks.org/dynamic-memory-allocation-in-c-using-malloc-calloc-free-and-realloc/&#34;&gt;Tutorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: PE4: structures&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Linux: 7.1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Lab 6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3/30/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Dynamic memory allocation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.geeksforgeeks.org/linked-list-set-1-introduction/&#34;&gt;Tutorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Dynamic memory allocation with structures&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Linked lists: add/search&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;13&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4/6/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Linked lists: delete&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Linux: 56-59&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Thursday has Monday schedule&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Linked lists: ordered lists&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Project 3 posted on Wed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Th: Lab 7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Project 2 due on Wed midnight&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;14&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4/13/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Easter break – NO CLASS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;All&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No class on Mon (Easter break)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: &lt;a href=&#34;https://etown.zoom.us/j/964329827?pwd=aEU2Tjg5ZzVkL3phRGl2OUR2VlZPdz09&#34;&gt;Zoom Q&amp;amp;A, password cs222&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: &lt;a href=&#34;https://etown.zoom.us/j/182360925?pwd=aXJhRzlVMzQyOFBCT2V2bVF4ZWxNZz09&#34;&gt;Zoom Q&amp;amp;A, password cs222&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;15&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4/20/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Lab 8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;All&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Exam 2 on Fri&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Exam 2 Preview&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Exam 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;16&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4/27/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Final review 1, Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;All&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Project 3 due on Wed midnight&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Final review 2, Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Schedule</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/ds200/schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/ds200/schedule/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Note this tentative schedule is subject to change. Please check the schedule regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Week&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Starting&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Topics&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Reading&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Notes&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1/13/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Course introduction and overview&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;DSS Ch. 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;HW 1 posted on Mon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Introduction to data science – the history and trend&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Python crash course – the basics&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1/20/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: MLK Day, NO CLASS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;DSS Ch. 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Python – functions, lambda expression and classes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Lab 1 (Python exercises)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1/27/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: NumPy – arrays and array indexing&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;DSS Ch. 4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;HW 1 due on Mon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: NumPy – operations&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PDA Ch. 4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;HW 2 posted on Mon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Lab 2 (NumPy exercises)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2/3/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Pandas – Series and DataFrames&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PDA Ch. 5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Final project topic search started&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Pandas – More on DataFrames&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Pandas – Groupby, Merging, Joining and Concatenating&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2/10/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Pandas – Operations, data input and output&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PDA Ch. 6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;HW2 due on Mon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Pandas exercises&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;HW3 posted on Mon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Lab 3 (Pandas exercises)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2/17/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Data visualization by using Matplotlib&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PDA Ch. 8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Paper presentation reading list posted&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Data visualization by using Seaborn&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Data visualization by using Pandas&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2/24/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Lab 4 (Data visualization)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;DSS Ch. 5, 6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;HW 3 due on Mon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Statistics – the basics&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Final project proposal due on Mon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: More on statistics and probability&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3/2/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Spring break. NO CLASS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Spring break. NO CLASS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Spring break. NO CLASS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3/9/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Exam 1 preview&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;DSS Ch. 11&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Exam 1 on Wed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Exam 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Class Canceled&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3/16/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Class Canceled&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;DSS Ch. 14&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Final project midterm check due on Fri&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Introduction to machine learning&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ISLR Ch. 2 &amp;amp; 3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Bias &amp;amp; Variance; machine learning with Python&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3/23/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Linear regression&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;DSS Ch. 16&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Linear regression exercises&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ISLR Ch. 4.1-4.3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Logistic regression&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3/30/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Lab 5 (Logistic regression)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;DSS Ch. 12&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;HW 4 posted on Mon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: K Nearest Neighbors&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ISLR Ch. 4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Lab 6 (KNN)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;13&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4/6/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: K Means&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;DSS Ch. 19&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No Fri class, Thur has Mon schedule&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Lab 7 (K Means)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ISLR Ch. 10 &amp;amp; 9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Th: Support vector machine (SVM)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;14&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4/13/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Easter break – NO CLASS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Notes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No class on Mon (Easter break)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: SVM exercises&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;HW 4 due on Mon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Lab 8 (SVM)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;HW 5 posted on Mon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;15&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4/20/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Exam 2 preview&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;DSS Ch. 24&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Exam 2 on Wed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Exam 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Paper presentation group 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;16&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4/27/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Paper presentation group 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;HW 5 due on Mon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Final project presentation group 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Final report and revised code due on Fri.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Final project presentation group 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Schedule</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/ds300/schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/ds300/schedule/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Note this tentative schedule is subject to change. Please check the schedule regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Week&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Starting&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Topics&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Reading&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Notes&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8/24/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Lec1 - Course introduction and overview&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ch. 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mon: HW1 out&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Lec2 - Introduction to data mining&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Final project topic search started&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Lec3 - Data&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8/31/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Lec4 - Data Warehousing&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ch. 2, lecture notes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Lec5 - SQL and Data Extraction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Lec6 - Data Preprocessing&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9/7/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: PE1 - Data Preprocessing Exercises&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ch. 3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mon: HW1 due, HW2 out&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Lec7 - Regression Part I&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Start project proposal writing&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Lab 1 (SQL and data preprocessing)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9/14/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Lec8 - Regression – Part II&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ncss.wpengine.netdna-cdn.com/wp-content/themes/ncss/pdf/Procedures/NCSS/Multiple_Regression.pdf&#34;&gt;Multiple Regression&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: PE2 - Regression Exercises&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ncss-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/themes/ncss/pdf/Procedures/NCSS/Ridge_Regression.pdf&#34;&gt;Ridge Regression&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Lab 2 (Regression)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9/21/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Professional Development Day - No Classes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ch. 4.1 – 4.6 &amp;amp; Ch. 4.9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mon: HW2 due, HW3 out&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Lec9 - Classification Part I&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Lec10 - Classification Part II&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9/28/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: PE3 - Classification Exercises&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ch. 4.10 – 4.12&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mon: project proposal due&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Lec11 - Ensemble Techniques&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Lab3 (Classification)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10/5/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: PE4 - Ensemble Techniques Exercises&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ch. 7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mon: HW 3 due, Paper presentation reading list out&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Lec12 - Clustering&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: PE5 - Clustering Exercises&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10/12/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Lab4 (Clustering)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Exam 1 Preview&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Exam 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Exam 1 on Fri&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10/19/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Lec13 - Association Rule Learning&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ch. 6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Professional Development Day - No Classes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: PE6 - Association Rule Learning Exercises&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Final project midterm check due on Fri&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10/26/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Lab5 (Association Rule)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sebastianraschka.com/Articles/2015_pca_in_3_steps.html&#34;&gt;PCA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mon: HW 4 out&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Lec14 - Dimensionality Reduction: PCA&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Lec15 - Dimensionality Reduction: LDA&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11/2/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: PE7 - Dimensionality Reduction Exercises&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ch. 4.7 – 4.8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Lab6 (Dimensionality Reducion)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Intro to Deep Learning&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11/9/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Lec16 - Artificitial Neural Networks&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://adventuresinmachinelearning.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/An-introduction-to-neural-networks-for-beginners.pdf&#34;&gt;Neural Networks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mon: HW 4 due, HW 5 out&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: PE8 - ANN Exercises&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Lab7 (ANN)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;13&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11/16/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Lec17 - CNN&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://deeplearning.net/tutorial/deeplearning.pdf&#34;&gt;CNN Ch. 6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: PE9 - CNN Exercises&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Th: Lab8 (CNN)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;14&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11/23/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Exam 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;All notes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mon: HW5 due, Exam 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Thanksgiving - No Classes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Thanksgiving - No Classes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;15&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11/30/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Paper presentation group 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Paper presentation group 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Final project presentation group 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;16&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;12/7/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Final project presentation group 2 (9:00 AM - 10:30 AM)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Final report and revised code due on Fri&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Schedule</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/ds420/schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/ds420/schedule/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Note this tentative schedule is subject to change. Please check the schedule regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Week&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Starting&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Topics&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Reading&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Notes&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8/24/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Lec1 - Course introduction and overview&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://peilong.github.io/files/ds420/Reading1-IntroToHadoop.pdf&#34;&gt;Reading1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mon: HW1 out, Start project topic search&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Lec2 - Introduction to Big Data&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Lec3 - Hadoop Ecosystem&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8/31/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Lec4 - HDFS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://peilong.github.io/files/ds420/Reading2-MR.pdf&#34;&gt;Reading2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Lec5 - MapReduce&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: PE1: MapReduce Exercise&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9/7/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Lab 1: MapReduce&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://peilong.github.io/files/ds420/Reading3-Hive.pdf&#34;&gt;Reading3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mon: HW1 due, HW2 out, Start project proposal writing&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Lec6 - Apache Pig&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Lec7 - Apache Hive&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9/14/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: PE 2: Pig Exercise&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://peilong.github.io/files/ds420/Reading4-Pig.pdf&#34;&gt;Reading4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Lab 2: Pig&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Lec8 - NoSQL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9/21/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Professional Development Day - No Classes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;DAS Ch.1, 2 and 3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mon: HW2 due, HW3 out&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Lec9 - Hbase&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Lec10 - MongoDB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9/28/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Lec11 - Intro to Apache Spark&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;DAS Ch.4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mon: Final project proposal due&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Lec12 - Spark RDD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Paper presentation reading list out&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Lec13 - Spark DataFrame&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10/5/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: PE 3: Spark DataFrame Exercise&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;DAS Ch.6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Lab 3: Spark DataFrame&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Lec14 - Spark Machine Learning&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10/12/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Lec15 - Spark Linear Regression&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;DAS Ch.8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mon: HW3 due, HW4 out&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Lec16 - Spark Logistic Regression&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Exam 1 Preview&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10/19/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Exam 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;DAS Ch.8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Exam 1 on Mon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Professional Development Day - No Classes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Lec17 - Spark Tree Classifiers&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Final project midterm check due on Fri&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10/26/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: PE 4: Spark Trees&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;DAS Ch.7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Lab 4: Spark Trees&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Lec18 - Spark K-Means&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11/2/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Lec19 - Apache Flume&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;DAS Ch.7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mon: HW4 due, HW5 out&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Lec20 - Apache Kafka&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Lec21 - Spark Streaming&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11/9/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: PE 5: Streaming&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://peilong.github.io/files/ds420/Reading5-NLP.pdf&#34;&gt;Reading 5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Lab 5: Streaming&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Lec22 - NLP&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;13&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11/16/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Lec23 - NLP with Spark&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://peilong.github.io/files/ds420/Reading5-NLP.pdf&#34;&gt;Reading 5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: PE 6: NLP&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Th: Lab6: NLP&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;14&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11/23/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Exam 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;All notes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mon: HW5 due, Exam 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Thanksgiving - No Classes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Thanksgiving - No Classes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;15&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11/30/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Paper presentation group 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Paper presentation group 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Final project presentation group 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;16&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;12/7/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Final project presentation group 2 (2:30 - 4:00 PM)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Final report and revised code due on Fri&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs121/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs121/software/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;java-se-development-kit-v8&#34;&gt;Java SE Development Kit v8.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accept the license and download the correct version for your system. Available as a free download at:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/java/javase/downloads/jdk8-downloads-2133151.html&#34;&gt;http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/java/javase/downloads/jdk8-downloads-2133151.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;eclipse-ide&#34;&gt;Eclipse IDE&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Java Integrated Development Environment, available as a free download at: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eclipse.org/downloads/&#34;&gt;http://www.eclipse.org/downloads/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eclipse &amp;amp; Java Environment are available on the computers in the Esbenshade 281, Hoover 108 and Nicarry 208 computer laboratories and in the Computer Science commons area (E284).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs222/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs222/software/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You need an Integrated Development Environment (IDE) that contains a GCC compiler, and a machine that runs Ubuntu Linux system in this course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many IDEs you can choose, e.g., Eclipse, Code::Blocks, Visual Studio, and CLion, etc, but for the purpose of in-class demonstration, I will stick with Visual Studio on Windows and Xcode on MacOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;for-windows-users&#34;&gt;For Windows Users&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IDE&lt;/strong&gt;: Visual Studio 2017 (community) and up: &lt;a href=&#34;https://visualstudio.microsoft.com/vs/&#34;&gt;https://visualstudio.microsoft.com/vs/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/strong&gt;: 1) Windows and Ubuntu 16.04 (or newer) dual-boot systems; OR 2) running Ubuntu on a virtual machine (e.g. virtualbox); OR 3) Ubuntu App on Windows 10.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;for-macos-x-users&#34;&gt;For MacOS X Users&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IDE&lt;/strong&gt;: Xcode - download from App Store. Make sure you have the Xcode Command Line tools installed. &lt;a href=&#34;http://osxdaily.com/2014/02/12/install-command-line-tools-mac-os-x/&#34;&gt;http://osxdaily.com/2014/02/12/install-command-line-tools-mac-os-x/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;for-linux-users&#34;&gt;For Linux Users&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You already have the whole world.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the software and operating systems are available on the computers in the Esbenshade 281, Hoover 108 and Nicarry 208 computer laboratories and in the Computer Science commons area (E284).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/ds200/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/ds200/software/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;anaconda-distribution&#34;&gt;Anaconda Distribution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this course the only software you will need to install and play with is the Anaconda Distribution. It is a popular data science platform that consists of almost all the packages you will ever need in Python and R. Find the download link for your system from here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.anaconda.com/distribution/&#34;&gt;https://www.anaconda.com/distribution/&lt;/a&gt;. You must download the Python 3.x version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anaconda Distribution is available on the computers in the Esbenshade 281, Hoover 108 and Nicarry 208 computer laboratories and in the Computer Science commons area (E284).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/ds300/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/ds300/software/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;anaconda-distribution&#34;&gt;Anaconda Distribution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this course the only software you will need to install and play with is the Anaconda Distribution. It is a popular data science platform that consists of almost all the packages you will ever need in Python and R. Find the download link for your system from here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.anaconda.com/distribution/&#34;&gt;https://www.anaconda.com/distribution/&lt;/a&gt;. You must download the Python 3.x version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anaconda Distribution is available on the computers in the Esbenshade 281, Hoover 108 and Nicarry 208 computer laboratories and in the Computer Science commons area (E284).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;jupyter-notebook-included-in-anaconda&#34;&gt;Jupyter Notebook (included in Anaconda)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Jupyter Notebook server is hosted at: &lt;a href=&#34;http://cs64.etown.edu:8000&#34;&gt;http://cs64.etown.edu:8000&lt;/a&gt;. Note that you need to VPN into campus network if visiting from off campus. If you are a member of the class, your default user name on the server is: your last name followed by first name initial, e.g. Taylor Swift&#39;s account is &amp;ldquo;swiftt&amp;rdquo;, and the default login password is &amp;ldquo;pass&amp;rdquo;. Reset your password immediately after login.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;other-software&#34;&gt;Other software&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will be introduced as the course goes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/ds420/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/ds420/software/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;use-software-on-the-campus-server&#34;&gt;Use software on the campus server:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hortonworks Data Platform (HDP): &lt;a href=&#34;http://adal.etown.edu:8080&#34;&gt;http://adal.etown.edu:8080&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PySpark enabled Jupyter Notebook: &lt;a href=&#34;http://adal.etown.edu:12345&#34;&gt;http://adal.etown.edu:12345&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;install-hdp-sandbox-by-yourself&#34;&gt;Install HDP Sandbox by yourself:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Docker Engine: &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.docker.com/engine/install/&#34;&gt;https://docs.docker.com/engine/install/&lt;/a&gt;.
Find the correct installation guide for your operating systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hortonworks Data Platform (HDP) on Sandbox version 2.6.5: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cloudera.com/downloads/hortonworks-sandbox/hdp.html&#34;&gt;https://www.cloudera.com/downloads/hortonworks-sandbox/hdp.html&lt;/a&gt;
Choose the correct installation type on Docker (less resource demanding than a virtual machine). The recommended configuration is 4 CPUs and 8 GB of free RAM; however, 2 CPU and 6 GBs of RAM should be enough for our case. Reducing the amount of RAM will make some of the services unavailable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow along the tutorial to install HDP on docker engine: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cloudera.com/tutorials/sandbox-deployment-and-install-guide/3.html&#34;&gt;https://www.cloudera.com/tutorials/sandbox-deployment-and-install-guide/3.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;install-pyspark-on-jupyter-notebook&#34;&gt;Install PySpark on Jupyter Notebook:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Checkout my tutorial on Github: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Peilong/PySparkOnJupyter/blob/master/README.md&#34;&gt;https://github.com/Peilong/PySparkOnJupyter/blob/master/README.md&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ChainSDI: A Software-Defined Infrastructure for Regulation-Compliant Home-Based Healthcare Services Secured by Blockchains</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/publication/2019-ieee-chainsdi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/publication/2019-ieee-chainsdi/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Review of Secure and Privacy-Preserving Medical Data Sharing</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/publication/2019-ieee-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/publication/2019-ieee-review/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Blockchain Future for Secure Clinical Data Sharing: A Position Paper</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/publication/2019-sdn-nfvsec-position/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/publication/2019-sdn-nfvsec-position/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A programmable policy engine to facilitate time-efficient science DMZ management.</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/publication/2018-fgcs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/publication/2018-fgcs/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EQuery: Enable event-driven declarative queries in programmable network measurement</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/publication/2018-noms-equery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/publication/2018-noms-equery/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CareNet: Building Regulation-Compliant Home-Based Healthcare Services with Software-Defined Infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/publication/2017-chase/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/publication/2017-chase/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Virtual Measurement Function scheduling in software-oriented measurement environment</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/publication/2017-icc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/publication/2017-icc/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing Virtual Network Functions for 100 GbE Network Using Multicore Processors</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/publication/2017-ancs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/publication/2017-ancs/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Measurement for 100Gbps Links Using Multicore Processors</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/publication/2016-fgcs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/publication/2016-fgcs/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CareNet: Building a Secure Software-defined Infrastructure for Home-based Healthcare</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/publication/2016-sdn-nfv/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/publication/2016-sdn-nfv/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CareNet: Building a Secure Software-defined Infrastructure for Home-based Healthcare</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/publication/2017-sdn-nfvsec/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/publication/2017-sdn-nfvsec/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>P4GPU: Acceleration of programmable data plane using a CPU-GPU heterogeneous architecture</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/publication/2016-hpsr-p4gpu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/publication/2016-hpsr-p4gpu/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/project/deep-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/project/deep-learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Duis posuere tellus ac convallis placerat. Proin tincidunt magna sed ex sollicitudin condimentum. Sed ac faucibus dolor, scelerisque sollicitudin nisi. Cras purus urna, suscipit quis sapien eu, pulvinar tempor diam. Quisque risus orci, mollis id ante sit amet, gravida egestas nisl. Sed ac tempus magna. Proin in dui enim. Donec condimentum, sem id dapibus fringilla, tellus enim condimentum arcu, nec volutpat est felis vel metus. Vestibulum sit amet erat at nulla eleifend gravida.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nullam vel molestie justo. Curabitur vitae efficitur leo. In hac habitasse platea dictumst. Sed pulvinar mauris dui, eget varius purus congue ac. Nulla euismod, lorem vel elementum dapibus, nunc justo porta mi, sed tempus est est vel tellus. Nam et enim eleifend, laoreet sem sit amet, elementum sem. Morbi ut leo congue, maximus velit ut, finibus arcu. In et libero cursus, rutrum risus non, molestie leo. Nullam congue quam et volutpat malesuada. Sed risus tortor, pulvinar et dictum nec, sodales non mi. Phasellus lacinia commodo laoreet. Nam mollis, erat in feugiat consectetur, purus eros egestas tellus, in auctor urna odio at nibh. Mauris imperdiet nisi ac magna convallis, at rhoncus ligula cursus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cras aliquam rhoncus ipsum, in hendrerit nunc mattis vitae. Duis vitae efficitur metus, ac tempus leo. Cras nec fringilla lacus. Quisque sit amet risus at ipsum pharetra commodo. Sed aliquam mauris at consequat eleifend. Praesent porta, augue sed viverra bibendum, neque ante euismod ante, in vehicula justo lorem ac eros. Suspendisse augue libero, venenatis eget tincidunt ut, malesuada at lorem. Donec vitae bibendum arcu. Aenean maximus nulla non pretium iaculis. Quisque imperdiet, nulla in pulvinar aliquet, velit quam ultrices quam, sit amet fringilla leo sem vel nunc. Mauris in lacinia lacus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suspendisse a tincidunt lacus. Curabitur at urna sagittis, dictum ante sit amet, euismod magna. Sed rutrum massa id tortor commodo, vitae elementum turpis tempus. Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Aenean purus turpis, venenatis a ullamcorper nec, tincidunt et massa. Integer posuere quam rutrum arcu vehicula imperdiet. Mauris ullamcorper quam vitae purus congue, quis euismod magna eleifend. Vestibulum semper vel augue eget tincidunt. Fusce eget justo sodales, dapibus odio eu, ultrices lorem. Duis condimentum lorem id eros commodo, in facilisis mauris scelerisque. Morbi sed auctor leo. Nullam volutpat a lacus quis pharetra. Nulla congue rutrum magna a ornare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aliquam in turpis accumsan, malesuada nibh ut, hendrerit justo. Cum sociis natoque penatibus et magnis dis parturient montes, nascetur ridiculus mus. Quisque sed erat nec justo posuere suscipit. Donec ut efficitur arcu, in malesuada neque. Nunc dignissim nisl massa, id vulputate nunc pretium nec. Quisque eget urna in risus suscipit ultricies. Pellentesque odio odio, tincidunt in eleifend sed, posuere a diam. Nam gravida nisl convallis semper elementum. Morbi vitae felis faucibus, vulputate orci placerat, aliquet nisi. Aliquam erat volutpat. Maecenas sagittis pulvinar purus, sed porta quam laoreet at.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>External Project</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/project/example-external-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/project/example-external-project/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>P4GPU: Accelerate packet processing of a P4 program with a CPU-GPU heterogeneous architecture</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/publication/2016-ancs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/publication/2016-ancs/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network measurement for 100 GbE network links using multicore processors</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/publication/2017-fgcs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/publication/2017-fgcs/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transformer: Run-time reprogrammable heterogeneous architecture for transparent acceleration of dynamic workloads</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/publication/2015-jpdc-transformer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/publication/2015-jpdc-transformer/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HeteroSpark: A heterogeneous CPU/GPU Spark platform for machine learning algorithms</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/publication/2015-nas-heterospark/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/publication/2015-nas-heterospark/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study of Image Segmentation Algorithm Based on Textural Features and Neural Network</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/publication/2010-icicci/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/publication/2010-icicci/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
