<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CS 121 Computer Science I | Peilong Li</title>
    <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs121/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs121/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>CS 121 Computer Science I</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2019 Peilong Li</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://Peilong.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>CS 121 Computer Science I</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs121/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Overview</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs121/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs121/overview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-coverage&#34;&gt;Course Coverage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fundamental concepts of computer organization, machine-level representation of data, algorithmic development and structured programming are presented with an emphasis on the syntactic and execution characteristics of the Java programming language, including data types; arithmetic operators and assignment; input/output, selection and iteration constructs; procedural abstraction; arrays; object-oriented programming and class design; and library usage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;student-learning-outcomes&#34;&gt;Student Learning Outcomes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of the course, students will be able to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apply knowledge of computing and mathematics, including common data structures and basic algorithms, to solve problems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design, implement, and evaluate a computer-based system, process, component or program to meet desired needs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Describe fundamental principles of the cycle of designing, implementing, compiling, and testing code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn to adhere to standards of style and documentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop an understanding of data types and basic operations in an object-oriented programming language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give examples of contributions of mathematics and computer science to the modern world&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use inductive or deductive reasoning to formulate solutions to problems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Model real-world phenomena mathematically and computationally&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manipulate strings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use basic I/O constructs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apply Boolean algebra and selection statements to problem solving&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apply loop statements to problem solving&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apply static methods to improve code design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apply arrays to store aggregate data for problem solving&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use procedural and object-oriented programming paradigms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Policy Statements</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs121/policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs121/policy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-announcements--discussion&#34;&gt;Course Announcements &amp;amp; Discussion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All course announcements will be posted via the Canvas Announcements page – you are responsible for checking the email updates (or app notifications) from Canvas regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discussions can be made via the Canvas Discussion page – you should never post complete programs to Discussion page (only general questions are permitted).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Need to DM (direct message) me? Join my Discord Q&amp;amp;A server: &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/32KEYEn&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;attendance-policies&#34;&gt;Attendance Policies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attendance is expected of every student at every lecture.  Students are responsible for all content covered in class as well as assigned book chapters.  Students should come to class with their text books, having read the material to be covered that day.  Students who have not prepared for class may be asked to leave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except in the case of documented emergencies, neither exams nor in-class labs can be made up afterwards.  For excused absences, students must arrange to take the exam or do the lab before the normally scheduled time.  Arrangements must be made with the instructor at least two weeks prior to the scheduled time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students are expected to maintain an attitude of respect at all times toward their colleagues, the equipment, and the instructor.  Students are expected to refrain from using the computers for non-course related purposes during class time and will be penalized 1% of the final grade for each occurrence.  Cell phones and similar devices should be turned off before entering the classroom.  Students who use offensive language, misuse computing facilities, or are otherwise disruptive of the classroom will be asked to leave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;statement-on-school-closure&#34;&gt;Statement on School Closure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the event that classes do not meet because Elizabethtown College is closed or delayed due to inclement weather or some other emergency, the slides that would have been covered during the missed classes will posted through Piazza group.  Students are expected to do the assigned reading, review the slides, and e-mail the instructor with any questions.  There will also be an opportunity to ask questions about the material when classes resume.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a scheduled exam or lab is missed, it will normally be made up on the day that classes resume.  If the College is closed on a day when a project is due, the project due date will also normally be extended until the day when classes resume.  If circumstances render either of these makeup policies unreasonable, the instructor will send an e-mail explaining an alternative makeup opportunity to each student’s Elizabethtown e-mail account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;statement-on-plagiarism&#34;&gt;Statement on Plagiarism&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please refer to the Student Handbook for the college’s policy.  All projects and assignments must be completed by students individually, without assistance from anyone other than the instructor.  Students can discuss the course material with each other at a conceptual level, but each student must do his or her own work.  For projects, exams, and all other activities in the course, students are expected to act according to the official policy on academic dishonesty and the highest standards of personal integrity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first infraction of academic honesty in this course will carry a penalty of a 0 for the project, lab, or exam in question and a reduction of a full letter grade in the final grade.  If a second infraction occurs, the students involved will fail the course, and the instructor will seek the maximum penalty possible under the college’s regulations, up to and including expulsion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;statement-on-disability&#34;&gt;Statement on Disability&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elizabethtown College welcomes otherwise qualified students with disabilities to participate in all of its courses, programs, services, and activities. If you have a documented disability and would like to request accommodations in order to access course material, activities, or requirements, please contact the Director of Disability Services, Lynne Davies, by phone (361-1227) or e-mail &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:daviesl@etown.edu&#34;&gt;daviesl@etown.edu&lt;/a&gt;. If your documentation meets the college’s documentation guidelines, you will be given a letter from Disability Services for each of your professors.  Students experiencing certain documented temporary conditions, such as post-concussive symptoms, may also qualify for temporary academic accommodations and adjustments. As early as possible in the semester, set up an appointment to meet with the instructor to discuss the academic adjustments specified in your accommodations letter as they pertain to my class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;statement-on-religious-observances&#34;&gt;Statement on Religious Observances&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The College is eager to facilitate individual religious beliefs and practices whenever possible while retaining course student learning outcomes. It is your responsibility to meet with the class instructor in advance to request arrangements related to your religious observances that may conflict with this class, and to make appropriate plans to make up any missed work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grading Policies</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs121/grading/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs121/grading/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;grading-weights&#34;&gt;Grading Weights&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final grade for this course depends upon the grades and scores earned on course components weighted as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;15%&lt;/strong&gt;: 3 equally weighted projects - 5% for each.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;15%&lt;/strong&gt;: 10 equally weighted in-class labs – 1.5% for each lab.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20%&lt;/strong&gt;: 2 equally weighted lab tests - 10% for each test.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;23%&lt;/strong&gt;: 2 midterm exams: 10% for lower grade, and 13% for higher grade.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5%&lt;/strong&gt;: Pop quizzes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2%&lt;/strong&gt;: Persistence. Attendance and in-class question answering.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20%&lt;/strong&gt;: Final exam.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grades will be computed by rounding numerical percentages to the nearest integer and applying the following table:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Letter&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Range&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Letter&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Range&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Letter&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Range&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;93-100&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;80-82&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;67-69&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;90-92&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;77-79&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;63-66&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;87-89&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;73-76&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;60-62&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;83-86&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;70-72&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0-59&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-Note&#34;&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;projects&#34;&gt;Projects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All projects are team projects in this course. For each project, all students must form teams of two (or three in the case of an odd number of students). Students are permitted to select their own teams; however, no two students may partner up for more than one project. In other words, each team will be different for each project. Students should select their teams by using the Groups tab under People, on the Canvas webpage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teams are responsible for dividing their workload. Except under extreme circumstances, all members of the team will receive the same grade for each project. One member of each team is designated the leader. The files for each project should be zipped up and uploaded by the team leader using Canvas before the due date. Projects must not be stored in a public folder. All project submissions must follow the provided file name requirements or risk a score of 0. &lt;strong&gt;If the project does not compile, the student will receive a score of 0.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Projects will be graded based on the following criteria:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Correctness: Finding the right answer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Formatting:	Displaying the right answer according to instructions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Style and Documentation: Producing readable code with appropriate comments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, projects will be graded with the &lt;em&gt;diff&lt;/em&gt; utility. For that reason, it is imperative that project output matches sample output to the character.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Late assignment will lose 2^(n-1) points per day, including weekends and holidays. For example, -1 after 1 day, -2 after 2 days, -4 after 3 days … until 8+ days students will receive 0 score.  Under no circumstances should any student disclose their code, or copy the code written by other students or from an outside source. Both students will receive 0 score on the disclosed/copied assignment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-class-labs&#34;&gt;In-class Labs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All labs are to be done in class, with the assistance of the instructor. Each assignment will be given near the beginning of a class and must be uploaded to Canvas (&lt;a href=&#34;https://etown.instructure.com/&#34;&gt;https://etown.instructure.com/&lt;/a&gt;) before the end of the class. Exercises submitted after class is over will not be accepted. To receive full credit, a programming assignment must compile, but partial credit will be awarded based on the understanding of the material demonstrated by the student’s code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Schedule</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs121/schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs121/schedule/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Note this tentative schedule is subject to change. Please check the schedule regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Week&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Starting&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Topics&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Reading&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Notes&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1/13/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Course introduction and overview&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SC Ch. 1 and 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Introduction to computer science&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TJ Ch. 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Software development &amp;amp; Lab 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1/20/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: MLK Day, NO CLASS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SC Ch. 3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No class on Mon (MLK Day)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Data representation and data types&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TJ Ch. 2 and 3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Math operations &amp;amp; Lab 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1/27/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Boolean and character operations&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SC Ch. 3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Methods and string operations&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TJ Ch. 2, 3, 9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Lab 3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2/3/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Conditionals: if statement (part 1)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SC Ch. 4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Project 1 posted on Mon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Conditionals: if statement (part 2)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TJ Ch. 5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Lab 4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2/10/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Conditionals: switch statement&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SC Ch. 4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Flowchart and debugging&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TJ Ch. 5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Lab 5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2/17/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: While and do-while loops&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SC Ch. 5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Exam 1 on Friday&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Exam 1 preview; Q &amp;amp; A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TJ Ch. 7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Exam 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2/24/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: For loops&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SC Ch. 5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Project 1 due on Mon midnight&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Revisit for loops&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TJ Ch. 7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Project 2 posted on Mon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Lab 6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3/2/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Spring break. NO CLASS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://us.macmillan.com/books/9781250002495&#34;&gt;The Bug&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Spring break. NO CLASS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Spring break. NO CLASS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3/9/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Arrays&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SC Ch. 6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Lab test 1 on Fri&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: 2D arrays&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TJ Ch. 8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Lab test 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3/16/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Standard drawing library&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://introcs.cs.princeton.edu/java/stdlib/javadoc/StdDraw.html&#34;&gt;Tutorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Standard drawing library (cont.)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TJ Appendix B&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Lab 7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3/23/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Static methods&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SC Ch. 8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Overloading methods&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TJ Ch. 4, 6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Lab 8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3/30/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Dr. Li on travel, finish online quiz&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SC Ch. 9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Project 2 due on Mon midnight&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Classes and objects&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TJ Ch. 10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Project 3 posted on Mon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Lab 9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;13&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4/6/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Object-oriented programming&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tutorialspoint.com/java/java_object_classes.htm&#34;&gt;Tutorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No Fri class, Thur has Mon schedule&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Algorithms&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TJ Ch. 11&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Th: Lab 10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;14&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4/13/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Easter break – NO CLASS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.javawithus.com/tutorial/searching-and-sorting-arrays&#34;&gt;Tutorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No class on Mon (Easter break)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Searching&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TJ Ch. 12&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Lab test 2 on Fri&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Lab test 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;15&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4/20/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Sorting&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Notes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Exam 2 on Fri&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Exam 2 preview&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TJ Ch. 13&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Exam 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;16&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4/27/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M: Final review 1, Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;All Notes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Project 3 due on Mon midnight&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W: Final review 2, Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F: Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs121/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs121/software/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;java-se-development-kit-v8&#34;&gt;Java SE Development Kit v8.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accept the license and download the correct version for your system. Available as a free download at:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/java/javase/downloads/jdk8-downloads-2133151.html&#34;&gt;http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/java/javase/downloads/jdk8-downloads-2133151.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;eclipse-ide&#34;&gt;Eclipse IDE&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Java Integrated Development Environment, available as a free download at: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eclipse.org/downloads/&#34;&gt;http://www.eclipse.org/downloads/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eclipse &amp;amp; Java Environment are available on the computers in the Esbenshade 281, Hoover 108 and Nicarry 208 computer laboratories and in the Computer Science commons area (E284).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
