<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CS 495 Honors Projects in Computing | Peilong Li</title>
    <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs495/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs495/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>CS 495 Honors Projects in Computing</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2019 Peilong Li</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://Peilong.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>CS 495 Honors Projects in Computing</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs495/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Overview</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs495/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs495/overview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-coverage&#34;&gt;Course Coverage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This course is a directed project or study requiring faculty acceptance of a proposal with a final report and defense of work. It is intended as an advanced research course for Computer Science majors and a prerequisite for Honors in the Discipline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;student-learning-outcomes&#34;&gt;Student Learning Outcomes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of the course, students will be able to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apply knowledge of computing and mathematics appropriate to the discipline, including common data structures and basic algorithms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analyze a problem and identify and define the computing requirements appropriate to its solution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design, implement, and evaluate a computer-based system, process, component or program, including operating systems and database systems, to meet desired needs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Communicate effectively with a broad range of audiences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Engage in continuing professional development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Policy Statements</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs495/policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs495/policy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-announcements--discussion&#34;&gt;Course Announcements &amp;amp; Discussion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All course announcements will be posted via the Canvas Announcements page – you are responsible for checking the email updates (or app notifications) from Canvas regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discussions can be made via the Canvas Discussion page – you should never post complete programs to Discussion page (only general questions are permitted).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Need to DM (direct message) me? Join my Discord Q&amp;amp;A server: &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/32KEYEn&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;attendance-policies&#34;&gt;Attendance Policies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attendance is expected of every student at every meeting. Students should come to meetings prepared to explain their progress and discuss appropriate technical issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;statement-on-school-closure&#34;&gt;Statement on School Closure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the event that classes do not meet because Elizabethtown College is closed or delayed due to inclement weather or some other emergency, the slides that would have been covered during the missed classes will posted through Piazza group.  Students are expected to do the assigned reading, review the slides, and e-mail the instructor with any questions.  There will also be an opportunity to ask questions about the material when classes resume.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a scheduled exam or lab is missed, it will normally be made up on the day that classes resume.  If the College is closed on a day when a project is due, the project due date will also normally be extended until the day when classes resume.  If circumstances render either of these makeup policies unreasonable, the instructor will send an e-mail explaining an alternative makeup opportunity to each student’s Elizabethtown e-mail account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;statement-on-plagiarism&#34;&gt;Statement on Plagiarism&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please refer to the Student Handbook for the college’s policy.  All projects and assignments must be completed by students individually, without assistance from anyone other than the instructor.  Students can discuss the course material with each other at a conceptual level, but each student must do his or her own work.  For projects, exams, and all other activities in the course, students are expected to act according to the official policy on academic dishonesty and the highest standards of personal integrity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first infraction of academic honesty in this course will carry a penalty of a 0 for the project, lab, or exam in question and a reduction of a full letter grade in the final grade.  If a second infraction occurs, the students involved will fail the course, and the instructor will seek the maximum penalty possible under the college’s regulations, up to and including expulsion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;statement-on-disability&#34;&gt;Statement on Disability&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elizabethtown College welcomes otherwise qualified students with disabilities to participate in all of its courses, programs, services, and activities. If you have a documented disability and would like to request accommodations in order to access course material, activities, or requirements, please contact the Director of Disability Services, Lynne Davies, by phone (361-1227) or e-mail &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:daviesl@etown.edu&#34;&gt;daviesl@etown.edu&lt;/a&gt;. If your documentation meets the college’s documentation guidelines, you will be given a letter from Disability Services for each of your professors.  Students experiencing certain documented temporary conditions, such as post-concussive symptoms, may also qualify for temporary academic accommodations and adjustments. As early as possible in the semester, set up an appointment to meet with the instructor to discuss the academic adjustments specified in your accommodations letter as they pertain to my class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;statement-on-religious-observances&#34;&gt;Statement on Religious Observances&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The College is eager to facilitate individual religious beliefs and practices whenever possible while retaining course student learning outcomes. It is your responsibility to meet with the class instructor in advance to request arrangements related to your religious observances that may conflict with this class, and to make appropriate plans to make up any missed work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grading Policies</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs495/grading/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs495/grading/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;grading-weights&#34;&gt;Grading Weights&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final grade for this course depends upon the grades and scores earned on course components weighted as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20%&lt;/strong&gt;: Project proposal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10%&lt;/strong&gt;: Milestone 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10%&lt;/strong&gt;: Milestone 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10%&lt;/strong&gt;: Milestone 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;30%&lt;/strong&gt;: Final project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20%&lt;/strong&gt;: Final paper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grades will be computed by rounding numerical percentages to the nearest integer and applying the following table:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Letter&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Range&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Letter&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Range&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Letter&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Range&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;93-100&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;80-82&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;67-69&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;90-92&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;77-79&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;63-66&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;87-89&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;73-76&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;60-62&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;83-86&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;70-72&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0-59&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grades for the proposal, milestones, final project, and final paper will be recorded in Canvas (&lt;a href=&#34;https://etown.instructure.com/)&#34;&gt;https://etown.instructure.com/)&lt;/a&gt;. Students may compute their current average by using these scores with the weights listed above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;proposal&#34;&gt;Proposal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All work is individual in this course. Each student, working with the instructor, will formulate the outline of a project. The plan for this project including goals should be written up and presented as a formal proposal due on the date specified in the course schedule. It should be turned in as a Word, LaTex, or PDF file and uploaded into Canvas before 11:59pm on the due day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;milestones&#34;&gt;Milestones&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the project has been proposed and approved, each student will have to present a document and give an oral presentation for each of three milestones. The document should be turned in as a Word, LaTeX, or PDF file. This document should be included in a zip file that also contains appropriate code. This zip file should be uploaded into Canvas before 11:59pm on the due date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Milestone&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Content&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Required hardware and software&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Desired features&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Expected timeline&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Implementation of essential features&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Working code&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Evidence of good software engineering and design&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Final features (no features should be added after Milestone 3)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Testing and debugging plan&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;final-project-and-paper&#34;&gt;Final Project and Paper&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A working version of the source code will be submitted by compressing it in a zip file and uploading that file onto Canvas before 11:59pm on the final project due date. Likewise, a paper of at least 8 pages (2,000 words) describing the purpose of the project, previous work done in the area, implementation details, successes, failures, and potential future work should be submitted. It should be turned in as a Word, LaTex, or PDF file and uploaded into Canvas before 11:59pm on the final project due date.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Schedule</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs495/schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs495/schedule/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Note this tentative schedule is subject to change. Please check the schedule regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Week&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Starting&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Activities&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Notes&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1/13/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Research&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1/20/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Research&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1/27/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Research&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Proposal Due Mon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2/3/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Design&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2/10/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Design&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2/17/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Design&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Milestone 1 Due Mon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2/24/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Spring Break&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3/2/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Implementation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3/9/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Implementation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3/16/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Implementation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Milestone 2 Due Mon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3/23/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Implementation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3/30/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Implementation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;13&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4/6/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Implementation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Milestone 3 Due Mon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;14&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4/13/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Testing and Debugging&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;15&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4/20/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Testing and Debugging&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;16&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4/27/20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Testing and Debugging&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Paper and Project Due&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proposal Requirements</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs495/proposal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs495/proposal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;specifications&#34;&gt;Specifications&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For details, please refer to &lt;a href=&#34;https://Peilong.github.io/files/cs400_495/cs400_495_proposal_guide.pdf&#34;&gt;Proposal Requirements&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
