<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CS 230 Computer Architecture | Peilong Li</title>
    <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs230/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs230/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>CS 230 Computer Architecture</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2019 Peilong Li</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://Peilong.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>CS 230 Computer Architecture</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs230/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Overview</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs230/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs230/overview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-coverage&#34;&gt;Course Coverage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An introduction to the foundational principles of computer architecture, including the design and organization of processors, memory hierarchies, input/output systems, and multiple CPU systems. Learn the core components that make up modern computer systems, including the CPU, GPU, memory, buses, and storage. Learn how to optimize performance, analyze trade-offs, and appreciate the historical and societal context of computing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;student-learning-outcomes&#34;&gt;Student Learning Outcomes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of the course, students will be able to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;apply Boolean algebra and digital logic principles to design and analyze combinational and sequential circuits, demonstrating their ability to solve complex computing problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;design and implement arithmetic and logic units using digital logic, including creating optimal solutions for adders, ALUs, and memory elements while evaluating performance trade-offs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;develop proficiency in assembly language programming using the HACK language, including writing, debugging, and optimizing low-level code to create computing-based solutions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;analyze computer system organization by understanding the interaction between processors, memory, and I/O systems, enabling them to evaluate architectural design choices and their performance implications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;work collaboratively to design and implement computer architecture components, making informed decisions about trade-offs while effectively communicating technical solutions in professional contexts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Policy Statements</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs230/policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs230/policy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-schedule&#34;&gt;Course Schedule&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most up-to-date course schedule will be posted on course website schedule page: &lt;a href=&#34;https://peilong.github.io/courses/cs230/schedule/&#34;&gt;https://peilong.github.io/courses/cs230/schedule/&lt;/a&gt;. Students are responsible for checking the schedule regularly. Schedule page will include: 1) teaching topics for each meeting; 2) reading assignments for each week and 3) special notes on specific days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-announcements--discussion&#34;&gt;Course Announcements &amp;amp; Discussion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All course announcements will be sent to your Etown email accounts via Canvas Announcements. You are responsible for signing up for this service and checking your emails regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have created a Microsoft Teams channel (&lt;a href=&#34;https://teams.microsoft.com/l/team/19%3aa8cdd959c2e249a989d401e20fc95524%40thread.tacv2/conversations?groupId=81ffa3c7-aa45-454a-b495-7f43c78e5024&amp;amp;tenantId=1d884f12-a0d7-42f0-8b15-3a91c853bcb5&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;) to facilitate course related discussion.  Discussions are encouraged to be posted on the &amp;ldquo;QA&amp;rdquo; channel from Teams. Private instant messages can be sent directly to your recipient by search your recipient&amp;rsquo;s name on the &amp;ldquo;search&amp;rdquo; bar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;attendance-policies&#34;&gt;Attendance Policies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attendance is expected of every student at every lecture. Students are responsible for all content covered in class as well as assigned book chapters. Due to their nature, pop quizzes cannot be made up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except in the case of documented emergencies, neither exams nor in-class labs can be made up afterwards.  For excused absences, students must arrange to take the exam or do the lab before the normally scheduled time.  Arrangements must be made with the instructor at least two weeks prior to the scheduled time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students are expected to maintain an attitude of respect at all times toward their colleagues, the equipment, and the instructor.  Cell phones and similar devices is prohibited from using during lecturing time.  Students who use offensive language, misuse computing facilities, or are otherwise disruptive of the classroom will be asked to leave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;statement-on-school-closure&#34;&gt;Statement on School Closure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the event that classes do not meet because Elizabethtown College is closed or delayed due to inclement weather or some other emergency, the slides that would have been covered during the missed classes will be posted through Canvas.  Students are expected to do the assigned reading, review the slides, and e-mail the instructor with any questions. There will also be an opportunity to ask questions about the material when classes resume.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a scheduled exam or lab is missed, it will normally be made up on the day that classes resume.  If the College is closed on a day when a project is due, the project due date will also normally be extended until the day when classes resume.  If circumstances render either of these makeup policies unreasonable, the instructor will send an e-mail explaining an alternative makeup opportunity to each student’s Elizabethtown e-mail account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;statement-on-academic-integrity&#34;&gt;Statement on Academic Integrity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out the up-to-date statement from: &lt;a href=&#34;https://catalog.etown.edu/content.php?catoid=30&amp;amp;navoid=1605#Academic_Judicial_System&#34;&gt;Elizabethtown College Catalog, &amp;ldquo;Academic Judicial System&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;statement-on-the-use-of-chatgpt-and-generative-ai-tools&#34;&gt;Statement on the Use of ChatGPT and Generative AI Tools&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The use of GenAI tools like ChatGPT to generate source code is prohibited for your assignments in this course unless otherwise noted in the syllabus. Therefore, your instructor will consider it a violation of academic integrity to use a GenAI tool for any purpose that is not explicitly outlined in assignment instructions. While this new technology can be very useful in certain contexts, it is important to make sure that its usage in the classroom setting is limited in order to ensure that you are doing original work and developing your critical thinking skills. In circumstances in which AI usage is permitted in class, you must acknowledge that usage and provide the chatbot with credit when it is a cited source. For instance, to cite ChatGPT in APA, the APA provides some direction at &lt;a href=&#34;https://apastyle.apa.org/blog/how-to-cite-chatgpt&#34;&gt;https://apastyle.apa.org/blog/how-to-cite-chatgpt&lt;/a&gt;. If you have any questions or uncertainty over the use of AI in this course, please reach out to the instructor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;respect-for-diversity&#34;&gt;Respect for Diversity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is my intent that students from all backgrounds and perspectives be well served by this course, that students&amp;rsquo; learning needs be addressed both in and out of class, and that the diversity that students bring to this class be viewed as a resource, strength, and benefit. I also intend to present materials and activities that respect diversity: gender, sexuality, disability, age, socioeconomic status, ethnicity, race, and culture. Please let me know if there are ways to further serve the diverse needs you or other students may have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;religious-observances&#34;&gt;Religious Observances&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The College is eager to facilitate individual religious beliefs and practices whenever possible while retaining course student learning outcomes. It is your responsibility to meet with the class instructor in advance to request arrangements related to your religious observances that may conflict with this class, and to make appropriate plans to make up any missed work.   The following is a link from the Chaplain’s Office website where a list of Religious Holidays needing accommodations (if requested) is posted:  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.etown.edu/offices/chaplain/index.aspx&#34;&gt;https://www.etown.edu/offices/chaplain/index.aspx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mental-health-and-counseling-resources&#34;&gt;Mental Health and Counseling Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Counseling Services provides a broad range of counseling and mental health support services that facilitate students&amp;rsquo; personal, social, and academic development. The licensed mental health professionals provide short-term individual counseling, group counseling, crisis intervention, and consultation to currently enrolled students for no additional charge. Counseling services are provided in a confidential and diversity-affirming environment to help students address a variety of mental health, situational, and developmental concerns. The office is located in the Baugher Student Center, Suite 216. Appointments can be made in person or by calling 717-361-1405. Urgent walk-in services are also available. To access the after-hours crisis services, please call the 24/7 Campus Security number of 717-361-1111. For more information, please visit &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.etown.edu/offices/counseling&#34;&gt;www.etown.edu/offices/counseling&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ada-statement&#34;&gt;ADA Statement&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elizabethtown College is committed to providing access for all students to courses, programs, services, and activities. If you have a documented disability such as a learning disability, chronic illness, or a new circumstance such as a concussion and would like to request accommodations, contact Lynne Davies, Director of Disability Services by phone (717-361-1227) or e-mail (&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:daviesl@etown.edu&#34;&gt;daviesl@etown.edu&lt;/a&gt;). The Office of Disability Services can provide resources to you and facilitate communication with faculty about reasonable accommodations.  After meeting with the Office of Disability Services, students must set up an appointment to meet with me, the instructor, to discuss the accommodations as they pertain to our class.  Common accommodations may include extra time on exams, an alternate exam location, the ability to record class lectures, and access to content with a screen reader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;modifications-for-non-native-english-speakers&#34;&gt;Modifications for Non-native English Speakers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recognition of the diverse linguistic backgrounds of our international students, we offer several accommodations to ensure a fair and supportive learning environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exams: If you encounter unfamiliar terms not covered in class, the Testing Center proctors are authorized to assist with translations. This support aims to clarify the meaning without providing an advantage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oral Presentations: International students, along with those who have auditory processing challenges, may request extended time for presentations. You are also permitted to use written notes to aid your delivery. Time adjustments will be made on a case-by-case basis to ensure you can effectively convey your knowledge while staying within reasonable limits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you require these or other accommodations, please communicate your needs in advance so appropriate arrangements can be made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;title-ix&#34;&gt;Title IX&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elizabethtown College and its faculty are committed to creating a safe and open learning environment for all students. If you or someone you know has experienced sexual harassment, including sexual assault, dating or domestic violence, and stalking, please know that help and support are available. Etown strongly encourages all members of the community to take action, seek support, and report incidents of sexual harassment to the Title IX Office. You may contact the Title IX Coordinator at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:reedg@etown.edu&#34;&gt;reedg@etown.edu&lt;/a&gt; or learn more by visiting &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.etown.edu/offices/diversity/titleix/index.aspx&#34;&gt;https://www.etown.edu/offices/diversity/titleix/index.aspx&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please be aware that faculty members are required to disclose information about suspected or alleged sexual harassment or other potential violations of the College Sexual Misconduct Policies and Procedures to the Title IX Coordinator. If the Title IX Coordinator receives information about an incident, they will reach out to offer information about resources, rights, and procedural options as a member of the campus community. Community members are not required to respond to this outreach. If you, or another student you know, wishes to speak to a confidential resource who does not have this reporting responsibility, please contact Counseling Services at 717-361-1405.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grading Policies</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs230/grading/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs230/grading/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;grading-weights&#34;&gt;Grading Weights&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final grade for this course depends upon the grades and scores earned on course components weighted as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10%&lt;/strong&gt; : A number of in-class pop quizzes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5%&lt;/strong&gt; : Attendance and class participation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;15%&lt;/strong&gt;: 3 individual projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20%&lt;/strong&gt;: 3 team projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;30%&lt;/strong&gt;: 2 midterm exams.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20%&lt;/strong&gt;: Final exam.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grades will be computed by rounding numerical percentages to the nearest integer and applying the following table:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Letter&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Range&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Letter&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Range&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Letter&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Range&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;93-100&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;80-82&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;67-69&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;90-92&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;77-79&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;63-66&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;87-89&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;73-76&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;60-62&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;83-86&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;70-72&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0-59&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-Note&#34;&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;individual-or-team-projects&#34;&gt;Individual or Team Projects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Individual projects meant to be small and nibble, and are usually delegated to be warm-up exercises and self-reflections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For team projects, students must form a team of 2 members. Teams are responsible for dividing their workload fairly and meeting offline frequently. Documented meeting minutes have to be submitted as part of the deliverable. Students should select their teams by using the Groups tab under People, on the Canvas webpage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except under extreme circumstances, all members of the team will receive the same grade for each project. One member of each team is designated the leader. The files for each project should be zipped up and uploaded by the team leader using Canvas before the due date. &lt;strong&gt;If the project does not compile, the student will receive a score of 0.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Late Policy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, projects will be graded by the autograder. For that reason, it is imperative that project output matches sample output to the character.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Late assignment will lose &lt;img src=&#34;https://latex.codecogs.com/png.latex?%5Cdpi%7B150%7D%20%5Cfn_phv%20%5Clarge%202%5E%7B%28n-1%29%7D&#34; alt=&#34;equation&#34;&gt; points per day, including weekends and holidays. For example, -1 after 1 day, -2 after 2 days, -4 after 3 days … until 8+ days students will receive 0 score.  &lt;strong&gt;Under no circumstances should any student disclose their code, or copy the code written by other students or from an outside source. Both students will receive 0 score on the disclosed/copied assignment.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Schedule</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs230/schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs230/schedule/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;schedule&#34;&gt;Schedule&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note this tentative schedule is subject to change. Please check the schedule regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last updated: 01/10/2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Week&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Starting&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Topics&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Reading&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Notes&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/13/25&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;T: Lec1 - Course intro&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Ch 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;H: Lec2 - Boolean Algebra and Expressions&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/20/25&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;T: Lec3 - Switch and Logic Gate Implementation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Ch 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tue: P0 out&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;H: &lt;span style=&#34;color:red&#34;&gt;Dr. Li on travel; No Classes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/27/25&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;T: Lec4 - Number System and Conversions&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Ch 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tue: P0 due; P1 out&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;H: Lec5 - Boolean Addition&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2/3/25&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;T: Lec6 - Multi-bit and Multi-input Adders&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Ch 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;H: Lec7 - Boolean Substraction and ALU Design&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2/10/25&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;T: Lec8 - Time and Memory Elements&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Ch 3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tue: P1 due; P2 out&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;H: Lec9 - Registers and RAMs; Meet &amp;amp; Greet&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2/17/25&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;T: Lec10 - State Machine Design and Program Counter&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Ch 3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;H: Module Summary and Exam 1 Preview&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2/24/25&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;T: &lt;span style=&#34;color:green&#34;&gt;Exam 1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;H: &lt;span style=&#34;color:red&#34;&gt;Dr. Li on travel; No Classes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;3/3/25&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;T: &lt;span style=&#34;color:red&#34;&gt;Spring Break, No Classes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;H: &lt;span style=&#34;color:red&#34;&gt;Spring Break, No Classes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;3/10/25&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;T: Lec11 - Machine Language&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Ch 4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tue: P2 due; P3 out&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;H: Lec12 - HACK Machine Language&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;3/17/25&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;T: Lec13 - HACK Assembly 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Ch 4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;H: Lec14 - HACK Assembly 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;11&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;3/24/25&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;T: Lec15 - Computer Architecture 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Ch 5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tue: P3 due; P4 out&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;H: Lec16 - Computer Architecture 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;3/31/25&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;T: Lec17 - HACK Assembler Design 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Ch 6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;H: Lec18 - HACK Assembler Design 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;13&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;4/7/25&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;T: Lec19 - Special Topic 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tue: P4 due; P5 out&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;H: Lec20 - Special Topic 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;14&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;4/14/25&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;T: Module Summary and Exam 2 Preview&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;H: &lt;span style=&#34;color:green&#34;&gt;Exam 2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;15&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;4/21/25&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;T: &lt;span style=&#34;color:red&#34;&gt;Scholarship Day, No Classes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tue: P5 due&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;H: Course Summary and Final Preview&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;16&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;4/28/25&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;T: Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;H: &lt;span style=&#34;color:red&#34;&gt;No Classes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;17&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;5/5/25&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Monday: &lt;span style=&#34;color:green&#34;&gt;Final Exam 11 AM - 2 PM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Have a great summer!&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software</title>
      <link>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs230/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Peilong.github.io/courses/cs230/software/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-nand-to-tetris&#34;&gt;From NAND to Tetris&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nand2tetris.org&#34;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; contains all the lectures, project materials and tools necessary for building a general-purpose computer system and a modern software hierarchy from the ground up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;nand2tetris-online-ide&#34;&gt;NAND2Tetris Online IDE&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://nand2tetris.github.io/web-ide/chip/&#34;&gt;This&lt;/a&gt; new Integrated Development Environment is web-based, meaning that you don’t have to download anything: All the tools and files necessary for completing all the projects are available from your browser. The files that you&amp;rsquo;ll develop using this IDE will be saved automatically in your browser’s memory, and you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to download them to your local PC.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
